<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-09T21:52:55+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</id><title type="html">Ng Wei Shyang</title><subtitle>Just another Homo sapiens who are interested in life and death</subtitle><entry><title type="html">[Movie] Mr. Nobody: Choices</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/mr-nobody-choices/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Movie] Mr. Nobody: Choices" /><published>2018-09-08T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-09-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/mr-nobody-choices</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/mr-nobody-choices/">&lt;p&gt;Let me start this blog by asking a question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Is spending your time reading this blog a right choice?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, what is a choice? When we use the word &lt;em&gt;choice&lt;/em&gt;, does it mean we have other alternatives of spending our time besides reading this blog? What are the other alternatives? If there are a lot of other alternatives, why is it a right, or not a right choice to read this blog instead of other alternatives? What is the right choice even mean? Why is one choice more right than the others? What is the metric that we used to measure how right the choice is? What do we even want to achieve in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many questions we need to ask before we are even able to answer that simple question. Imagine, what will happen if the question is much more complex than this? What if the choice that we need to make are very important to our life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Before he was unable to make a choice because he didn't know what would happen. Now that he knows what will happen, he is unable to make a choice.&quot; — Nemo Nobody&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole movie of Mr. Nobody surrounds with the child, Nemo Nobody, at age 9, unable to make a choice between following his dad or mom after they divorce. He then thinks about what could happen if he chooses any one of the choices, and it leads to many different paths of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-09/train-station-choice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, it is only between choosing following his father or mother. If he chooses to follow his mother, he will meet a girl called Anna. Various choices he made will lead him to be together with Anna or not. However, if he chooses to follow his father, he will meet Jean and Elise. Again, various choices he made after that can lead him to be together with either one of them, or neither both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-09/wedding-choices.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of paths being shown in the movie, each is the results of the choices he made. The choices range from something as big as to date Jean or not to date after being rejected by Elise, to as small as confessing his love to Elise 10 seconds earlier or later. This movie shows the effect of the butterfly effect, which is a small change can lead to tremendous differences in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;A single snowflake can bend the leaf of the bamboo&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-09/boiling-eggs.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the movie, the butterfly effect even extends to the choices made by others. At one part of the movie, a factory worker decide to skip work, went home, and boil some eggs. The process of boiling eggs creates extra water vapor in the air, which lead to the rain few days after factory worker incident, exactly at the moment after Nemo receive a card with Anna’s phone number on it, which wash away the ink on the card, causing him to lost the last chance to see Anna again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every choices, one that you made yesterday night for what you going to have for your dinner, one that you made last Monday for should you skip your 8am class, one which you made a few months ago when you choose which new phone to buy, one which your parent choose if to intervene in your choices of course for continuing higher education, or one which your mother choose if she accept your father marriage proposal, would result in completely different outcome depending on the choices being made at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make choices every second of our life, and every single choice we made can result in a completely different outcome. A small mistake might destroy our life, so does a right choice. Beyond that, some of the choices are out of our control too, and these choices that made by someone else could even potentially ruin our day. If so, how can we even make sure that we are on the right path?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-09/chess.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life choices are like chess. In the beginning, we are all not good at playing chess. We often overlook the strategy of the opponent and lost the game. However, as we play more chess, the better we get at playing chess. The same goes for making life choices. As we grow older, we are better in making the right choices in achieving our goal at that time. Despite that, we might still lose a chess game. There are always people who are more experience than us. The same goes for making life choices, there are just too many variables that we can take into account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a particular chess game, the outcome of the game is totally depending on the choices that made by us and our opponent. To win a chess, not only we need to make the right move, the opponent needs to make the move which in our favors. There are times when we make all the best move we can ever make at that moment, with all the experience we had before that match, we just couldn’t win that match for the simple fact that the opponent is more experienced than us. However, how do we react to that match is also completely up to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Stoicism, it calls trichotomy of control. There are things that we have full control, things we have partial control and things we do not have control over. Winning a chess game is not something that we have full control over. For instance, the experience our opponent have in chess is totally not in our control. The match can happen when we are 10 years old, and our opponent is the chess world champion of that time, 60 years old, and had been playing chess since 6 years old. We just do not have any control over how many experiences our opponent has. We can’t simply make our opponent into a person who is only playing chess for the first time. If so, why does the experience of our opponent matters in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning the match is not in our total control too. Facing the same opponent, the world champion, even if we are playing chess since the day we born, playing it 18 hours per day, 7 days per week, the difference in experience is just too huge between us and the world champion. Despite our chances of winning is much higher than us playing chess for the first time, it does not guarantee that we will win the chess game. However, practice chess as much as we can, practice a healthy lifestyle so we can have a clear mind when we are playing chess and learn the most out of every match, and trying our hardest to get the most significant out of every single chess match we had is something that we had total control over. So, if we had done that, does winning the match matters anymore?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;In chess, it's called Zugzwang... when the only viable move... is not to move.&quot; — Nemo Nobody&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-09/zugzwang.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to chess rules, we have to make a move whenever it is our turn to make a move. There are times when Zugzwang happens, where the move that we can have is either disadvantage to us or lead us to lose the game. In this situation, choices do exists, but only a limited set of choices, which eventually lead us to the negative outcome of the situation. Facing that situation, no matter how calm we are in that situation, and how aware we are that we had made the best move which we can have in that given situation, we still have to make a choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads us to think, how should we make a choice? If losing the game not going to affect our emotion, and all the viable move lead to a negative outcome anyway, how should we choose one over another? Assume there are only 2 viable choices, one which can last us another 5 round before losing the game, another will lead us to lose the game in the next round. Is it more meaningful to last the match as long as possible, be the most persistent person in the world, do not give up until the last moment we can no longer persist anymore, or just lost in the next round, learn the lesson out of the match, move on to the next match, and try to win that match with the sum total experience of all the matches we had before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Young journalist: Everything you say is contradictory. You can't have been in one place and another at the same time. Of all those lives, which one is the right one?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Nemo Nobody: Each of these lives is the right one! Every path is the right path. Everything could have been anything else and it would have just as much meaning.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything could have been anything else. The one who had chosen to persist as long as he can could have just lost the game the next round and move on to the next match. The one who had chosen to end the match the next round could have persist as long as he could until the round which he had to lose the game. One is not more meaningful than the other, and the value is up to the person who made the choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same goes for life. I could have been studying hard during secondary school, and be a medical student right now. I could have not continued to pursue my higher education after my high school and is working right now. I could have been anything else, but no one is less real than the other. The me at this moment is the most real me to me at this moment, and that is all matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the chess matches we had, we could have won it all if we are lucky enough. But, those losing match, is also what shape us us, and what potentially contribute to the winning in the future. Each and every single choice we made, is equally meaningful to us, and us alone. It is only us alone that can end up in that exact moment, in that situation, made the decision which we had made in that situation, and it is what makes us unique. There is no single person in the world could have ended up in that situation at that exact moment and made that decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;At my age the candles cost more than the cake. I'm not afraid of dying. I'm afraid I haven't been alive enough. It should be written on every school room blackboard: Life is a playground - or nothing.&quot; — Nemo Nobody&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, nothing matters. Life is a playground, and if it is meaningful to you, it is all that matters.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Everything could've been anything else</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/images/post/2018-09/mr-nobody-laugh.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Game] Saya no Uta: Aesthetic</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/game-saya-no-uta-aesthetic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Game] Saya no Uta: Aesthetic" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/game-saya-no-uta-aesthetic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/game-saya-no-uta-aesthetic/">&lt;p&gt;In the last post, we had already discussed one of the works of Gen Urobuchi: Fate Zero. Today, we are going to discuss yet another work of Gen Urobuchi, which is Saya no Uta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saya no Uta is a visual novel, written by Gen Urobuchi, released in 2003. It is later translated to English in 2009. Saya no Uta is one of the signature work of Gen Urobuchi, besides Psycho-Pass, Madoka Magica, and Fate Zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a question, which I had been asked several times, in primary school, secondary school, or internet memes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;A curry that looks and taste like shit, a shit that looks and taste like curry, which would you choose?&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not have an answer for that. I fail to answer this question the first time being prompted to it and still fail to answer it now. No matter which choice I choose, it is still equally disgusting. Choosing the curry that we perceive as shit, can we even consume that? Choosing the shit that we perceive as curry, for we had already known the actual content of it, will we able to consume it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gen Urobuchi probably facing difficulties in making a decision for this question and start writing Saya no Uta. Joke aside, let us go through a summary of the story before we discuss this game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert!!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Following blog contains spoiler. If you had not played the game, continue at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the visual novel, Fuminori had a surgery operate on him after involving in an accident. The surgery leaves him with cognitive disorder due to brain damage. The symptoms of the disorder lead him to perceives the everything as rotten meat and horrific monster. The sense of it is not limited to touch, smell, look, taste and hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, in the hospital, he saw a beautiful young girl who looks like a real human to him. The young girl, not only looks like a human, smell like a human, and touching sensation feels like a human too. However, she is some disgusting monster in reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep down in Fuminori heart, he knows that she is not what she seems to be. In the game, he can choose to either let Saya heal him, perceiving the world back to what he suppose to perceives, and not able to see Saya anymore, or leaving him as it is, accepts Saya and accepts the world as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-to-choose&quot;&gt;Which to choose?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between curry and shit, we are unable to choose one, because we are not given enough context. Without context, either one seems disgusting to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the visual novel, the protagonist perceives the floor, the wall, his room, the hospital building, the world, everything, as disgusting, gore, rotten meat, for 24 hours per day, 7 days per week, 365 days per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine being him, being in the state of prolonged visual disgust, and in the midst of despair, a hope shows up. You see a visually desirable human. This human looks like a young girl, an arguably pretty one, and does not look like those horrific monster that made up from a pile of rotten meat. Since the time after your surgery, which you had already lost track of how long is it before, where it seems forever for you, for the first time, you see something desirable. At that moment, does anything matter anymore? 
in order
Back to the curry and shit, imagine you had the same cognitive disorder. You see the world as disgusting shit. Nothing in the world seems normal to you. You get really hungry. You eat as less as possible, barely enough for survival. You stay idle as long as possible to avoid calories burn. Suddenly, a bowl of curry appear in front of you, would you even bother to know what it actually made up of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the question that presented to us in this game. How will we act under such circumstances? Will we suicide, or will we go for whatever pleasurable to our senses, or will we stick to the objective aesthetic sense of the object?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have the answer, but I do not. However, we do not live in such a world, so what matter? Whatever choice you choose, if it is true for you, then it must be true, because the one who is making the choice is you, not me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Regarding to aesthetic - objective or subjective?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/images/post/2018-08/saya_no_uta.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Anime] Fate/Zero: Emiya Kiritsugu</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/anime-fate-zero-kiritsugu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Anime] Fate/Zero: Emiya Kiritsugu" /><published>2018-08-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-08-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/anime-fate-zero-kiritsugu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/anime-fate-zero-kiritsugu/">&lt;p&gt;I had finished this anime a few weeks ago. This is my second time watching this anime, the first during a few years ago. The plot written by Gen Urobuchi, animation animated by Ufotable, the song by Kalafina and composed by Yuki Kajiura, and everything else combined, is what makes this anime so great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the anime, I knew that I have to write a blog about the character, Emiya Kiritsugu. He is, in my opinion, the most correct, yet the most flawed character in the anime. He is also one of the most deeply constructed characters in the anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us take some time out, appreciate how correct, how flaw, and how well constructed this character is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beware, spoiler ahead!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; If you had not watch this anime, continue at your own risk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emiya-kiritsugu&quot;&gt;Emiya Kiritsugu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;childhood&quot;&gt;Childhood&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine yourself, growing up with a family of 2, your father and you. He is a mage, one who perform some experiment every day, which you believe can bring nothing but blessed to humanity. In your eye, he is like a hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your father had just moved to a new village. You make a few new friends. There are one within them, who are the opposite sex of yours and have a special place in your heart. You had a crush on her, and her existence is like a heavenly angel to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-08/stay_with_you_until_then.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seemingly, your future looks super bright. You are going to continue your father research, and the result of the research is going to bring tremendous blessed to humanity. You also had the crush of yours, telling you that, she is going to watch you grew up. Everything seems good, not until the day, the day on which you woke up, being told by your father, not to go to the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-wasnt-suppose-to-be-like-this&quot;&gt;It wasn’t suppose to be like this&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-08/shirley_zombie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this day, which you found your crush, turning into a zombie, after consuming a drug produced by your father research, which supposedly brings nothing but blessed to humanity. Isn’t your father research supposedly bring blessing to humanity? Why is your crush turning into a zombie? Wasn’t she supposed to stay with you until you grew up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of confusion, you run to the church and look for the priest. In the meantime, your crush had the zombie virus spread to the other villager. In a matter of seconds, the village is destroyed by the mage association and church executor. Fire burning all around the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-08/burning_village.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ground which had your footstep on it, the coconut tree which you used to climb, the riverside which where your memory of you and your friend comes from, the church which you go to when you have trouble, and the tiny house, a few houses left to the church, right beside the coconut tree, where your crush used to live, had all turn into nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You went to your father, seeking out the truth of his research, realizing the research is nothing close to what it claims to be. Rather, it was just a research seeking for a controllable dead apostle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is like a dream, a nightmare. Where are the promises from your father research? Where does the future lies, where you had now realize that the research of your father is nothing close to the promises that had been told to you? You had your father killed because you know that, not having your father killed, such event will repeat sometimes in the future. Contrary to the promises, it brings nothing but misery to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;good-bye-shirley&quot;&gt;Good bye, Shirley&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You soon adopted by a woman who is like a freelancer to the mage association. She is like a mother to you, and she teaches you all kind of skills that you need to assist her in her job. You also adopted the philosophy of utilitarianism, which is to sacrifice the less to bring blessing to the more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You work very hard, killing the people who are like your father, uses magic to bring harm to people. You keep doing it, believing that, by following this path, you can avoid all the tragedies that happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-08/kiritsugu_shooting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, you realize, that type of people can be seen everywhere. The path that you follow,  can only do so little, and not more than that. Following your path, you also end up killing your mother (the freelancer of mage association), knowing that it is the correct thing to do, in order to avoid bringing misery to the people in the airport she is landing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun Fact&lt;/strong&gt;: The episode where he kills her mother is release during mother’s day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the need to kill the only one who you are emotionally attached to, you continue because you believe that in order to save someone, you must sacrifice someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-omnipotent-wish-granting-machine&quot;&gt;The omnipotent wish granting machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, you heard of the Holy Grail, the holy existence that can grant any wishes. You believe that it can achieve your wish, which is world peace, without the need to sacrifice more people. You soon strive to fight towards the holy grail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You fight hard, doing anything, backstabbing, bombing a building, deception, betrayal, all these, in order to attain Holy Grail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shirley-i-had-made-it&quot;&gt;Shirley, I had made it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you had attained the holy grail. Inside the holy grail…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
	Grail: &quot;Three hundred on one ship, two hundred on another…&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;Five hundred total passengers and crew. Plus Kiritsugu Emiya. Let’s assume that these five hundred and one people are humanity’s last survivors. Giant holes simultaneously open up in the both ships crippling them. Kiritsugu alone has the skills needed to repair a ship. Now then, Which one of the ships would you choose to fix?&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;Simple… the one holding three hundred people.&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;As soon as you make that decision, the two hundred passengers on the other ship, kidnap you and take you prisoner. They demand you fix there ship first, what will you do?&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;...&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;You will kill all two hundred passengers… that is correct. That is the Kiritsugu Emiya we know.&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;Next, the surviving three hundred passengers abandon their damaged craft they split themselves between two new ships. They continue their journey This time, there are two hundred on one, and one hundred on the other. But again, holes open the howls of both ships at exactly the same time…&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;Wait...&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;The hundred in the smaller ship take you prisoner. And like the other, demand you to fix their ship first. Now, what will you do?&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;You already know… aren’t you?&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;Yes. You’ve made the right decision.&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;No! that’s impossible! How can that be the right decision?! Two hundred survived, but three hundred died so they could live! The scales are tipped the wrong way!&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;No. Your calculations were correct. You made a choice to sacrifice the few to save the many. Isn’t that right? Kiritsugu Emiya? You have consistently chosen to kill those on the lighter side of the scales. Even if it meant to leave a long trail of the bodies behind you in your wake, if it save lives, the lives that you've saved, must have been worth more than you destroyed.&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;This… this is what you wanted to show me?&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;Yes. This is your truth. The answer that lies within Kiritsugu Emiya. The course of action that should be taken by the Grail as an all-powerful wish granter.&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;No! No this is not what I want! I want that there would be another way to save the world! That’s why I believed… the miracle was my only hope.&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;Your wish cannot include a method you yourself don’t already know. If your wish is to save the world, it must be done in a manner that you can fully comprehend.&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Kiritsugu: &quot;Like hell! How in the hell… can you call that a miracle?!&quot;
	&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	Grail: &quot;The deed you try so hard to accomplish and fail to do on your own, can be accomplished in a scale beyond the power of any man. If that is not a miracle, what is?&quot;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-08/kiritsugu_despair.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment, you realize the grail is not omnipotent wish granting machine, and it is no miracle. You reject the grail simply because the cost is bigger than the reward. It is also at this moment, you realize, what you had been doing is flawed. The calculation is correct, except it is wrong. To save 200 people, you had sacrifice 300 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-man-who-just-want-to-help-other&quot;&gt;The man who just want to help other&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if you were him, what would you do? You lost your ideal, for you had realized it is not correct. You too, lost the hope that you had placed upon the omnipotent wish granting machine, for it is no miracle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, you just want to help others. Now, you end up with nothing. As much as you know saving someone require to sacrifice others, the cost that you had paid are simply far greater than the reward that it had given to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, in the end, you are able to inspire someone to inherit your dream — becoming the ally of justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Well, I want to be ally of justice.&quot; — Emiya Kiritsugu&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gen-urobuchi&quot;&gt;Gen Urobuchi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gen Urobuchi’s writing is known to be tragedy and nihilistic. These examples can be seen from Psycho Pass, Madoka Magica, Saya no Uta. Part of the reason for his writing is his experience of nearly dying in an epidemic when he is younger. In turn, he generally has a worldview of a crapsack world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;I have nothing but contempt for the deceitful thing men call 'happiness' and find myself with no choice but to push my characters, whom I pour my heart and soul out to create, into the abyss of tragedy.&quot; — Gen Urobuchi&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The near death experience of him, is what makes him drive his characters into the abyss of tragedy. Kariya and Kiritsugu from Fate Zero, Sayaka and Homura from Madoka Magica, Fuminori from Saya no Uta, all of these, are born from the contempt of Gen Urobuchi towards ‘happiness’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being said, Gen Urobuchi is a cynic. As much as I think Freudian Excuse is not an excuse, he actually wanted to create a happy story. In the midst of pushing his characters into the abyss of tragedy, he too, create hope for his characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander charging into the battle with Gilgamesh, despite knowing the fact that he cannot win at all. Kiritsugu continues fighting for his ideal, despite knowing that it probably not going to make any difference. Kyouko working hard to turn Sayaka back to a magical girl, despite knowing that it is almost impossible to do so. It is the struggling against the despair and tragedy, that create the most beautiful moment of that human being can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world can be a crapsack place, full of despair and suffering. There is no inherent meaning at all. Betrayal, deception, murder, genocide, all of these are just another day of human life. However, what keeping one going forward, is the hope that born within himself. It is the hope, the struggle against despair, struggle against nihilism, that brings the greatest strength to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine living in a totalitarian state, be it fictional (Oceania) or non fictional (Soviet Union), it seems nothing can be worse than that. People around you starving to death every single day. Rebellion seems useless against the armed army. But, to rebellion against the state, knowing the fact that you will never win against the armed army, the tiny hope that created by that action, inspire more rebellion army. For every rebellion army you inspire, they inspire more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-08/miracle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should the outcome be positive or negative, should the rebellion army able to overthrow the totalitarian state, does it matter anymore? For you, who had done your best, striving against the despair, and create hope for others, had shone for the strongest moment of your life. If you can only live once, why give in to the abyss of despair, instead of shine bright for all you can?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;If anyone ever tells me it’s a mistake to have hope, well then, I’ll just tell them they’re wrong. And I’ll keep telling them till they believe. No matter how many times it takes.&quot; — Madoka Kaname&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-kiritsugu&quot;&gt;Back to Kiritsugu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common theme of Gen Urobuchi is the backlash against utilitarianism. Sibyl System in Psycho Pass, Kyubey in Madoka Magica, and Kiritsugu in Fate Zero, these are the embodiment of utilitarianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of Sibyl System is to achieve the greatest happiness in the greatest number of people. Kyubey goal is to ensure the survival of the greatest number of lifeform. Kiritsugu is to save the greatest number of people possible. To achieve the goal, it often sacrifices a small number of people in order to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilitarianism, made a decision solely based on logic. This often leads to the need of putting aside emotions. Sibyl System, the collection of brain, make a decision without the interference of emotion. Kyubey, the alien lifeform, do not have emotion, to begin with. Kiritsugu, repress his emotion, carry out what he knows is the correct action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What different, is it from a machine, if human made a decision solely based on logic. Kiritsugu killing his father and mother, without hesitation, knowing that is the correct thing to do. He kills his assistant (in the grail) when given choices of 2 versus 1. He kills his wife and daughter (in the grail too), for it is 6 billion versus 2. What happiness can there be, if one acts like a machine, and repress all the emotion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;It has gradually become clear to me what every great philosophy up till now has consisted of – namely, the confession of its originator, and a species of involuntary and unconscious autobiography; and moreover that the moral (or immoral) purpose in every philosophy has constituted the true vital germ out of which the entire plant has always grown.&quot; — Friedrich Nietzsche, Beyond Good and Evil&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as his work is a backlash against utilitarianism, it is also the confession of his attitude towards utilitarianism. As much as he thinks utilitarianism is inhumane, he too, think utilitarianism is correct. This can be seen from his characters. The protagonist often does not reject utilitarianism, but strive towards a better solution than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Akane in Psycho Pass, accepted the Sibyl System, knowing without it, the society will go into chaos. However, she does warn Sibyl System, for they will replace Sibyl System with something even better in the future. Kiritsugu, adopted utilitarianism, but turn to the all-powerful wish granting machine, hoping for a miracle, for it can replace the role of utilitarianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine, you are traveling to an island. Upon reaching the island, the island had overtaken by some terrorist. For you are honor guest of the island, the terrorist offer you to shoot one of the hostages. If you do not shoot, they will kill all 20 hostages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a situation of 1 versus 19. If you kill 1, you save 19. However, all 20 will die if you do not shoot. In utilitarianism, your action can lead to saving 19 people, or your inaction will cause death to all 20 people. Inaction, too, is an action, and will dirty your hand, regardless of action or inaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In utilitarianism, facing such a situation, the correct answer is obviously to carry out the action. For the world is just a horrible place, if your action can make it a slightly better place, and you choose inaction, that is immoral too. In this horrible world, it is naive to think that you can run away from dirtying your hand. If dirtying your hand is certain, it is better to achieve moral and dirtying your hand than not achieving moral and still dirtying your hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, can we settle with just utilitarianism? Utilitarianism, not only require dirtying your hand to achieve moral, it also requires repress of emotion to achieve moral. If all 20 hostages are a child, and the only weapon given to you is a 15cm long knife, and with that weapon, it is unavoidable to kill a child without watching them struggling and screaming for life. In that case, will your emotion even allow you to carry out the action?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the contradiction appear within Gen Urobuchi. As much as he thinks it is correct, he too, think it is wrong. Accepting utilitarianism, is to accept the good intention of them to do good to the greatest number of people in the first place. Adopting utilitarianism, however, would result in nothing but misery to one who adopts it. Your inaction that causes by your emotion, is nothing but the origin of the good intention of one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-08/illya_pointed_with_gun.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The child, 6 years old, female, long hair, big eyes, sitting anxiously in front of you, waiting for you, who holding a 15cm long knife, to stab the knife into the soft stomach of her, pulling it out, hearing her screaming, and stabbing it again, into the other part of the stomach, again pulling it out, and watching the blood coming out from the eye and mouth of her, soon losing any energy to scream anymore, and struggle on the floor for other minutes before dying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone who avoid themselves from carrying out such cruel action, despite being able to save another 19 children, even the child is going to die anyway regardless of your action or inaction, is nothing but the pure emotion of one not wanting to do harm to the child. For the emotion is the origin of good intention, can we truly call them immoral?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may aware, I am taking intention as the benchmark of measuring good in an action. For one might have good intention but carry out bad actions, such as genocide, that is a whole topic for another day. However, if one does not have good intention, how often can the result of the action turn out to be good? Assuming one had bad intention, but turn out as good result, how many times can such happen, until the bad intention finally result in a bad result?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we accept utilitarianism, it does not mean we need to adopt it. Instead, we should continually strive to look for a better moral framework which can overcome the short of utilitarianism. Meanwhile, you can be satisfied with utilitarianism, you too, should not settle with just utilitarianism, given you had adopted it as your moral of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, one day in the future, we will be able to find out a better moral framework, while focusing on creating greatest good to the greatest number of people, it too, can take into account of human intention and human emotion, for emotion is what makes humanity beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;afterthought&quot;&gt;Afterthought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a Sunday morning before I start writing this article, I started thinking about Emiya Kiritsugu life. His life is nothing but misery, and I am unable to derive any meaning out of it. It makes me depressed by just thinking about it. That morning, I can’t even calm down my mind to read a book after hitting with the depressed emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly, I do not expect it to turn out to be so positive. I expect this to turn out to be immense depressing and misery. If someone would be had told me that this would turn out to be positive, I would not believe him. Now, I have more hope than at any time in my life could ever have. Like Madoka, if anyone tells me it’s a mistake to have hope, I too, will tell him that he is wrong, every single time. Shall us wish ourselves to shine brightly in our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, see you in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hey, Kerry. What do you want to be when you grow up?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/images/post/2018-08/kerry_shirley.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Book] 1984: Thought and Mind</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/book-1984-thought-and-mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Book] 1984: Thought and Mind" /><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/book-1984-thought-and-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/book-1984-thought-and-mind/">&lt;p&gt;Few day ago, I had written a 1984 analysis on social construct. Before start writing about the analysis, I had drafted out a few more point. However, as I start writing about social construct, I just can’t stop and it turn out to be a stand alone blog. So, this blog will be the analysis of the rest of the point that I had drafted initially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start the rest of the analysis, I will give a quick rundown of the book in case you had forget about the plot of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beware, spoiler ahead!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; If you had yet read this book, go and read the book before continue with this blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1984&quot;&gt;1984&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1984 taking place in year 1984, after world war 2. The world seperated into a total of 3 continents, namely Eurasia, Eastasia and Oceania. All of this 3 continents are ruled by similar totalitarian government. The story majorly taking place in Oceania, which ruled by an english socialist party, Ingsoc. All of these 3 continents has power enough to resist from the attack of other 2 continents combined, but are not strong enough to take over any other continent. Basically, they are in a deadlock where no one can conqueur others and cannot be conqueur by others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main character of the book is Winston Smith, who is a middle class outer party. Outer party is second in place of the class hierarchy in Oceania. The higher most being upper class Inner party, which made up of 2% of the population. Meanwhile, outer party made up of 13% of the population and lower class Proletariant made up of 85% of the population. The higher the class hierarchy, the more benefit they are entitled to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part 1, there are a lot of people around Winston simply dissapear during night, leaving no evidence of existence and without explaination. These people are thought criminal, who had thoughts which go against the party’s doctrine. The government also constantly manipulating the information that can be attain by the people. It is here where we are introduced with newspeak, which is a replacement of oldspeak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In second part, Julia, a girl who he meet in part 1, confess her love to Winston. After that, they start having sexual relationship, which is not allowed in Oceania. After that, they meet O’Brien, who is an inner party. After meeting O’Brien, they join the rebellion force. One day, while they are having conversation after having sex, they are captured by thought police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final part of the novel, Winston is capture into the Ministry of Love. In there, he go through three phases of reeducation, namely learning, understanding and acceptance. At first, he will be torture while being told the truth. It is here where Winston come to love O’Brien, who is his torturer because he stop torturing him. After that, he is left solitude and provided with everything he need, from hygiene to nutrition. It is here, he understand that Big Brother will take care of him. Finally, he is brought to Room 101 to face his biggest fear. Facing his biggest fear, he finally betray the last person who he had yet betray, which is Julia. After releasing from the Ministry of Love, he meet Julia. Upon finding Julia making the same decision as him, he learn the ultimate acceptance of Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thought-versus-deed&quot;&gt;Thought versus deed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought is what we think. Action is the actual thing that we do. When we carry out the action of our thought, it call deed. All deeds are voluntary action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inner party and outer party are under constant surveillance with the telescreen. The telescreen can capture every sound made above the very low whisper level and every action detail of them. When the telescreen capture any word spoke which does not align with Big Brother ideology, even if it is sleep talking, it would consider as thought crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the novel, Tom Parsons is a person who accept whatever had been told by the party without second thought. He appear to be someone who truly believe in the party ideology and doctrine. However, he is arrested for saying “Down with Big Brother” while sleeping. It is his own children who denounces him to the thought police. He is arrested even without having any action which misalign with Big Brother ideology. Ironically, he told Winston that he is proud for his own children for fulfilling their duty when imprisoned in the Ministry of Love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true question here is, should we arrest someone by just their thought? All of us, at some point of our life, have ill intent. We think of how to beat someone who talk ill about us. We think of how to revenge upon the bullier who bully us when we are child. We think of all kind of ill intent, and did not carry out actions of most of our thoughts, at least for most of us. By just thinking, we had yet carry out our action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, some of our thoughts are inevitable. Some of these thought are come as a natural instinct which reflect on the particular situation. For example, someone cut infront of us while driving without giving any indication. At that moment, most of the poeple would curse and develop the thought of slapping the driver. These instinct are almost inevitable without training ourselves to think otherwise. It is a reflection towards what happen at that very moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if we are given chance to stop at the side of the road with the driver, majority of us would had already calm down by the time we coming out from our car. This is because majority of our action are govern by reason. When we developed the thought of slapping the driver, we think of the consequences that we would need to face. We think of the driver hitting our car with sterling lock which result in financial lost. We think of the driver punching us back on our face which result in physical suffering. We think of getting into police station for involving in a fight, which result in energy lost. In the end, we came to the conclusion of not slapping the driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of our actions are govern by reason. When we think of having love affair, we think of the undesirable consequences upon partner finding out the love affair. However, there are those who cannot govern their actions by reason. Their ability of reasoning had been override by emotions. Most of them had in the past, actions govern by reason too. They repress their desire to do harm for long until they can no longer repress the desire. For once they convert thoughts into actions, they will need to face consequences of their actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, should we punnish people by just thought and thought alone wihtout deed? Does thought alone enough to determine the will of a person? Tom Parsons, for instance, how can we determine his will by just some word spoken while sleeping? Should we even punnish him if the thought are not truly govern by his reasoning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doublethink&quot;&gt;Doublethink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doublethink is the ability of thinking two contradictory meaning as the same. Quote of doublethink from the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;To know and not to know, to be conscious of complete truthfulness while telling carefully constructed lies, to hold simultaneously two opinions which cancelled out, knowing them to be contradictory and believing in both of them, to use logic against logic, to repudiate morality while laying claim to it, to believe that democracy was impossible and that the Party was the guardian of democracy, to forget whatever it was necessary to forget, then to draw it back into memory again at the moment when it was needed, and then promptly to forget it again, and above all, to apply the same process to the process itself—that was the ultimate subtlety: consciously to induce unconsciousness, and then, once again, to become unconscious of the act of hypnosis you had just performed. Even to understand the word—doublethink—involved the use of doublethink.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, there is huge emphasis on doublethink. Throughtout the story, we see a lot of example of the use of doublethink. An example of doublethink would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
	WAR IS PEACE &lt;br /&gt;
	FREEDOM IS SLAVERY &lt;br /&gt;
	IGNORANCE IS STRENGTH
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;War, by definition, is to inflict violence between two or more party. Size of party can be ranging from one to many person. Small scale war can be fighting between two person, while it can be as large scale as multiple country having war with multiple other country. Peace however, by definition, is the absense of violence. To live peace is to live without the worry of violence. If war is to inflict violence, and peace is the absense of violence, how can they be the same thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One intepretation from part 3 of the book would be as such. Constant war against two other continents would result in the use of resources. Depletion of resources would lead people to live in constant worry. While any two of these continents combined would not have enough power to take over any one of the continent, there is almost no risk in getting conqueue by others. It is this constant fear and worry in people that maintain peace within them. Revolution happen during peace, and revolution involve violence. To have war is to not have revolution and has no risk in getting conqueue, and hence to have war is to have peace itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the book, we also see the ministry of government are doing the opposite of the name of the ministry imply. Quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The Ministry of Peace concerns itself with war, the Ministry of Truth with lies, the Ministry of Love with torture and the Ministry of Plenty with starvation. These contradictions are not accidental, nor do they result from ordinary hypocrisy: they are deliberate exercises in doublethink.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another example of the practice of doublethink. This time, we will look at Ministry of love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a person caught commiting thought crime, they are arrested and imprison in Ministry of Love. While imprison in Ministry of Love, they will be torture. Love, by definition, is strong affection for another arising out of kinship or personal ties. With love, it arise one passion of doing good or inflict pleasure to the other which one has strong affection to. Torture, by definition, is the act of inflicting physical and psychological suffering to fulfill the desire of the torturer. So, how can one who has passion on doing good, inflicting pain to the target which the passion intended to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, to torture is to teach. It is through torture, one can become a part of the collective thinking of Big Brother. It is him, who become a part of the collective thinking, receive the ultimate good from the Big Brother, as the will of Big Brother, has become the will of he himself. It is out of love of the Ministry of Love towards the people, to inflict pain to the targets so they are able to receive the biggest good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From above, we can see the shadow of 2 things, namely relativism and idealism. Idealism will be discuss in the later part of this blog, so we will only focus on relativism here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doublethink, to a certain extend, require the thinking of relativism. To say black, is to refer the blackness of one black as relative to a lesser black. This can be apply to white, as refering whiteness of one white in relative to a black that has lesser white. Black and white, seems to be contradictory, are nothing but the different side of the same coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relativism can be seen in the war and peace example. The peace of war is peace as relative to the war that could arise from peace itself. Freedom is slavery can be understood as the freedom within slavery as oppose to the slavery to the hedonism within the context of freedom itself. Strength within the context of ignorance is strength as relative to the weakness found within the state of lack of ignorance. Upon finding the truth, ignorance no longer stay, and the strength gain from ignorance fade together with ignorance itself. What left after that, is the lack of strength as oppose to the existence of strength that comes with the ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question here to ask is, to what extend, we should apply relativism? Should we apply it to literally everything? Can there be alternative to this approach?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, I think relativism is true to a certain extend. However, if we approach things objectively, we are able to determine to what extend relativism should be apply. Ignorance is strength, for example, when approach objectively, will realize that the strength gain from ignorance is not ultimate strength. Strength gain from ignorance fade together with the dissapearance of ignorance. The true strength lays together with the truth, and to see the truth, and able to derive strength from it, is the ultimate strength that we should strive for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be seen in the blog, &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/book-1984-social-construct/&quot;&gt;1984: Social Construct&lt;/a&gt;, where the true freedom lays behind the lack of ingorance on freedom and slavery, and the will to power to overcome the slavery within the context of freedom. In this case, relativism is only applied to understand slavery within the context of freedom. What come after is to approach it objectively, and strive to overcome slavery within freedom, and hence achieving true strength that can no longer fade, unlike the strength that fade together with dissapearance of ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;idealism&quot;&gt;Idealism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;In philosophy, idealism is the group of metaphysical philosophies that assert that reality, or reality as humans can know it, is fundamentally mental, mentally constructed, or otherwise immaterial.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, idealism is the idea of everything happen in our mind, and our mind only. We, human, have concious. Our concious perceive existence through five senses. These senses include vision, smell, taste, hear and touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An apple, for example, do not perceive by us directly. Through vision, we develop a sense of roundness, redness and other characteristic of an apple in our mind. Through touch, we perceive the touching sensation of the texture of apple surface. Through smell, we smell the scenets of wax on the surface of apple. When we bite the apple, we taste the sweet flavors of the apple. When we hear a drop sound from the floor, we know the apple has drops to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following idealism, since we do not perceive things directly, everything must exists in our mind, and solely our mind. The apple mention above, exists only in our mind. If we believe that the apple do not exists, the apple do not exists. These believe can be seen from the part 3, where O’Brien force Winston to believe that two plus two equals five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice of Idealism by the party in 1984 act as a base for a lot of their arguments. Since everything exists solely in our mind, ill thought might as well have been an ill deed. For them, thought and action has not distintive differences since everything exists only in our mind. In fact, they are the same. It also act as the base of doublethink. It emphasis on the ability of thinking two contradictory thing as equal and to truly believe it, ignoring any other factor, for everything solely exists in our mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with Idealism is only focusing on logic, and logic only, without linking it back to reality. Their arguments always start with concious perceiving things throught five senses, instead of perceiving directly. Hence, everything must be only in our mind. However, in epistemology hierarchy, what come before perceiving things itself is existence exists, which they had rejected it. The error happen at the foundation of which their arguments based of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very often, people who commit this kind of error are emotion repressor. They repress the role of emotion that plays in reasoning. Their arguments often start with the wrong definition, and the arguments which follow the wrong definition, will nevertheless lead them to the wrong direction. This is where the role of emotion comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we create definition for a word, the definition only consists of a limited number of distintive characteristics of the actual thing itself. This is because of crow epistemology, which is the limitation of the number of things that we can hold at a time. If we make arguments solely with the definition itself, we will miss out all the other distintive characteristics of the thing. This is where emotion shines, which is call psycho epistemology. Psycho epistemology is the use of emotion that link the definition of the word back to the actual object, so the argument do not went to the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let give an example. A living things has life. Life is a process of self generated and self sustaining. Self generated mean the source of action come from the living things itself. Example, we eat food, food comes from outside, but the process of digesting the food happens within our body. Self sustaining is to sustain ourselves from confronting the lack of life, which is death. Human follow a set of actions for self sustaining, such as consume food and drink water. Plants, naturally grows towards the direction of sun to get it source of energy. If we fail to follow the set of actions, our life is gone, and our distinctive essences are gone too, but our body, which construct by chemical elements remain. Take a non living thing, statue for example, if we break it down, the distintive essences are gone, but the chemical elements which originally construct the statue remains. Hence, living thing are the same as non living thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the result when giving arguments with following the definition alone. With emotions, when we say living things, it will link the word “living things” to the actual living things which we have emotional attachment to, such as our pets, family, friends, etc. When the arguments follow the wrong direction, we will be able to ask ourselves, where did the definition comes from. Obviously, the definition of “process of self generated and self sustaining” for life is not everything about life, and we cannot include everything about life into definition due to crow epistemology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without definition, we will unable to make argument due to crow epistemology, which there are too many things to hold on to, and we are required to create definition for it. With psycho epistemology, we are able to link the definition back to the actual object, and hence, not leading the arguments to the wrong direction. So, whenever the conclusion of an argument does not align with reality, always ask the question “where did the definition comes from”, and you will be able to avoid leading argument to the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;language&quot;&gt;Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newspeak is the language that used in Oceania, created by the party. Newspeak had remove some of the unnecessary grammar from oldspeak (the english that are currently used by us), such as a specialize word to indicate the opposite semantic meaning of a word. Instead, they use “un” to indicate the opposite semantic meaning of a word, and “plus” and “doubleplus” to indicate different level of positive prefix. Therefore, instead of using “bad” to indicate opposite semantic meaning of “good”, “ungood” will be used instead. In oldspeak, excellent can be understood as very good. Magnificent, too, can be understood as very good. However, is excellent better good than magnificent or the otherwise is ambigious. Therefore, it is reduced to “plusgood” and “doubleplusgood” to indicate better good and better good than the previous good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we are not focusing on the grammar part of newspeak. We will focusing on how newspeak can affects thought of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main purpose of newspeak is thought control. Newspeak are carefully constructed to limit what human can think. The word “free”, exists in both newspeak and oldspeak. However, the word “free” cannot be used as if being used in oldspeak. In new speak, “free” can be refer to “without monetary cost” or “not affected with undesirable”. Example of such would be “buy one free one” or “the dog is free from lice”. However, the definition of “not affected with undesirable” cannot be used in political context because free will is non existence in Oceania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lead us to think how language plays a role in our thought. Things such as free will does not exists as an existence, rather as an idea. When we come up with a complex idea, we form a word to represent the idea. When people in the future learn the word that represent the complex idea, and come up with another complex idea that based on the complex idea which previously form, they form another word that represent it. In order to understand the latter word, one need to understand the idea which the word based on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the idea of free will in political context is removed from the language entirely, will we capable of thinking such complex idea? If the word removed is apple, we are still capable of thinking apple, not in word, but in other form of thought. We can form the image of apple in our mind, imagining the taste of it, and explaining it with it’s distinctive characteristics. This is because apple exists as an existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideas, on the other hand, does not exists as an existence. In order to be capable of thinking the idea, word are needed. However, in order to form the word, the idea which the word are going to represent requires to exists. The cycle of forming words for ideas, and creating ideas with the existing words are extremely slow. Once the meaning of “free will” in political context is removed from the language, there is almost impossible for anyone to be capable of thinking about that idea anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When newspeak are finalized into the final edition, and people who are capable of using old speak are removed entirely from the world, thought police are no longer needed. This is because people are no longer capable of commiting thought crime. People who originally would derive to the idea of “free will” with the existing word alone will not able to derive to it in Oceania due to the education and controlled environment in Oceania. This, perhaps, is the utopia that envision by Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;collectivism&quot;&gt;Collectivism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last idea is collectivism. The definition of collectivism from dictionary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;the practice or principle of giving a group priority over each individual in it&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collectivism is the practice of prioritize focusing on the collective group before the individual. As oppose to individualism, which prioritize focusing on individual before collective group. Practice of collectivism can be seen throughout a lot of other practices, which include communism, socialism, utilitarianism, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collectivism above however, are not exactly the collectivism which practice by Ingsoc. In the novel, Oceania is rulled by Ingsoc, and is govern by Big Brother. Big Brother however, is no where to be seen in the novel. In fact, no one in the novel knows, who exactly is Big Brother. There are numerous of unanswered question regarding to Big Brother, which include “does Big Brother exists?”, “is Big Brother a person or a group of people?”, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in the part 3 of the book, from the arguments of O’Brien, Big Brother exists, and exists in a collective way. Big Brother might be a person at the begining, and comes up with various ideology and doctrine. However, Big Brother represent the ideology and doctrine. The question of “does Big Brother exists, and if yes, who?”, is in fact, not important. In a sense, when Big Brother is mentions, it refers to its ideology and doctrine. Anyone can be Big Brother, and Big Brother itself is the collective will of the people who endorse the ideology and doctrine of Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This collectivism that practices by Ingsoc is interrelated to idealism. If Big Brother says two plus two equals five, then two plus two equals five in Oceania. While Big Brother is a collective, it also mean it is the collective of will which will for two plus two equals five, which itself becoming the will of Big Brother. As it is the will of Big Brother, and everything exists solely in mind, and it is the will of the collective mind, it became the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought criminal are sent to Ministry of Love for reeducation. Through the reeducation in Ministry of Love, he will no longer be the victim of the state. He will be reeducated to fully learn, understand, and total acceptance of Big Brother, and by doing that, he become a part of the collective group who endorse Big Brother. Hence, Big Brother will will become his will, and he will no longer suffer from the will of Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;putting-all-together&quot;&gt;Putting all together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The totalitarian communism in 1984 is what the worst totalitarian government can become. For them, power is not a mean, but an end, and their power is absolute and no longer can be overthrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If there was hope, it MUST lie in the proles, because only there in those swarming disregarded masses, 85 per cent of the population of Oceania, could the force to destroy the Party ever be generated.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hope of overthrowing the absolute power lies in the proles, but proles are constant sedated with various sensual pleasure. For proles to be able to reach the truth, education and ideas are needed. This however, are no longer possible due to thought control from newspeak. The idea of will to truth and free will will never exists anymore. Even if the very minority who are still capable of reaching that idea, had reach the idea, they will be arrested for thought crime and being reeducated, and becoming a part of Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice of doublethink also give them the illusion of living in peace. To be capable of reaching the idea of free will in political context, they need to question current situation in the very first place. With doublethink, they will not even question it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebellion army, by itself, is also a part of the will of Big Brother, and is used to kept Ingsoc in power. All of these combining together, with newspeak being finalized for thought control, and everyone had becoming a part of the collective will of Big Brother, this create the ultimate absolute power of Big Brother that is impossible to be overthrow. This, in fact, is the worst nightmare of a totalitarian government can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion, we had discuss various ideas in this blog, include thought versus deed, doublethink, relativism, idealism, how language affect our thought and collectivism. We see how all of this is being used in totalitarian government to remain their power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the questions to ask ourselves is, should communism and socialism be practice? To answer this question, ask ourselves, what is the role of government? What happen if government do not exists? If government do not exists, what kind of government do we want? Is communism or socialism that bad? Is democracy as good as what most people claim it to be? How can we further improve the government system that we have in today, to better achieve the role of the government that we had answer ourselves previously? Lastly, how can we avoid from what being potrayed in the book?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Two plus two equals five</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/images/post/2018-07/mind.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Book] 1984: Social Construct</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/book-1984-social-construct/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Book] 1984: Social Construct" /><published>2018-07-07T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-07-07T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/book-1984-social-construct</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/book-1984-social-construct/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been few weeks, perhaps months since I finish reading this book. It is one of the most facinating book that I had ever came across. I wanted to write an analysis about this book for quite some time, but had been occupied with a lot of things. Finally, I get to take a breath from all those things and decided to write this review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1984 is one of the best selling classic fiction written by George Orwell, first published in 1949. In the novel, George Orwell discuss about a lot of facinating idea that would jusut blow off our mind, thinking that why we never thought of it before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I start writing this blog, I had lay out a list of idea that I want to discuss. However, after I start writing about social hierarchy, I just can’t stop and it end up as a stand alone blog. There is little to no spoiler in this blog, so do enjoy it even if you had yet read the book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-hierarchy&quot;&gt;Social hierarchy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, there are a total of 3 class hierarchy, namely inner party, outer party and proletariant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inner party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inner party made up of 2% of the total population. The inner party have access to the most luxurious thing which outer party and proletariant do not have access to. These include spacious living quarter, personal servants, high quality food such as fine red wine, high quality coffee, etc. These are the benefit that both outer party and proletariant do not have access to. On top of that, the telescreen can be turn off (although it said to be unwise to turn off more than 30 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outer party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outer party made up of 13% of the total population. They are the middle class of Oceania. They do not have access to as much luxury as inner party. Instead of high quality food, they get low quality food such as synthetic coffee, gin, synthetic chocolate. Instead of spacious office, they work in cubicles. They are also under constant surveillance and has little to no personal privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proletariant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proletariant are made up of 85% of the total population. While inner party and outer party are under constant surveillance through the telescreen, proles quarter has little to no telescreen for surveillance. This reflect that the rulling party has little interested to cares about the proles. They are extremely poor. Most of them has little care about anything other than football, alcohol, lottery ticket, pornography, etc. They are constantly kept sedated with these sensual pleasure by the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;analysis&quot;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this class hierarchy sound familiar? Yes! The class hierarchy in Oceania resemblance the social status in the world that we are living in. In the world that we are living in, top 1% wealthiest of the population posses 40% of the wealth while bottom 80% posses only 7% of the wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-07/rich_lifestyle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inner party resemblance the top wealthiest population in our world. They have access to the most luxurious lifestyle that most people can’t afford. They have the biggest house, most expensive luxury car, best quality food, etc. Some of them even have private yachts and helicopter. These inner party are some of the most wealthy and powerful people on earth. They are the politicians, top management of corporate, investor, etc. Most of the power are aggregate in these group of people, and their decision can affect a lot of people, including you without you knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-07/middle_class.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the outer party resemblance the middle class. The middle class has decent job with decent income, just like the outer party who working for the party in one of the ministry. While most of the middle class can afford material thing to a certain extend, they are often in debt. Because of it, they will automatically work hard in order to pay off their debt. While the outer party drive by the fear of getting capture by the ruling party, the middle class drive by the fear of losing the material thing that they posses. They are like the slave or prisoner of the material world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-07/office_cubicles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proletariant resemblance the lower income population. Most of them have job, but not good enough to afford extra luxury like top and middle class do. Majority of them cannot afford buying a house. Many of them rent house and drive old car or take public transport. They work from 9 to 5 every week day like a machine. If there are something that driving them forward, it would be the false hope that given to them. These false hope are social construct that are designed to distract them from wanting to escape from the reality. False hope such that able to becoming the top wealthy person by sacrificing a part of their little earning. False hope such that giving them the short term sensual pleasure so they are able to withstand the suffering. False hope such that helping them to escape from the reality. They come in a form of lottery ticket, gambling, football, alcohol, sex, etc. Eventually, they are like a hamster on a wheel that trap in a cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inner party is one who has power to decide the will of Big Brother, while outer party and proletariant must obey the will. In our world, upper population are one in power with corporate or government, making decision and the employees or citizen must follow. Inner party also create things that can keep proletarians sedated with sensual pleasure. In our world, upper population are one who own lottery company or casino, giving false hope to the lower income group. They also create beer factory, selling these beer to the lower income group helping them to escape from the reality, while they enjoying the finest red wine, siting at the expensive, long, white marble table, inside the bungalow that they own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inner party or upper class seems like the best to live in, but which class is the worst to live in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the middle class get to enjoy luxury which the lower income group cannot afford, they are too trap with all the material matter. They are deeply trap in the system, perhaps even depper than the lower income group did. Credit card that they hold, house loan and car loan that they get, education loan that they lend, all these are what trapped them deeply in the system itself. They know that they are trapped, but they can no longer escape from it for various reason that they have. Just like the outer party that being protrayed in the book, while knowing the truth, could not escape due to the fear that are impose on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lower income group however, constantly drive by the false hope that given to them. They are unaware of the false hope, nor the truth, just living like a pleasure seeking animal. They are trap without they themselves knowing it. They live as if they are the most free people in the world, doing whatever they want, without caring much for thing that they do not want to care of. Just like the proletariants that being protrayed in the book, as long as they had done their job, they live their life the they want to. There are little to no telescreen in the quarter that they live in too. They are perhaps the most free group within all 3 category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, middle class might be the worst group to be. Being the group that long lost ignorance, they are trapped in a cycle that they can no longer escape. What good can it do to them for the little more luxury which they get to enjoy as oppose to the cost that they are paying for. Here, ignorance is perhaps the answer to the happiness, the mindless hapiness that can blindly pursue by our pleasure seeking natural instinct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrarily, upper class, from the surface, looks like having the most freedom compare to the other 2 social class. However, they are also bound by the conventional patriarchy hierarchy. Corporate leader need to follow all the rules set by the government. They too need to please other people to maintain their business and social standing. The same goes for politician, who need to constantly please the citizen to remain in power. Unless, they are dictator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dictator too are not free! They are bound to fail if they do not please the crook around him. He, who is a dictator, need to please the head of military to be in favor of him. He, who is a dictator, too need to please the influential individual who are powerful enough to be able to overthrow him. He too, being a dictator, are not truly free and bound by various constrain which they cannot escape from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why is one class seems better to live in than the others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without thinking twice, upper class seems the best to live in because the freedom that they are entitled to, as oppose to the middle and lower class. Lower class, seems to be better than middle class, for the reason of ignorance of their state of being trapped. At the same time, they have more freedom compare to the middle class. They careless about other thing and seeking for nothing but pleasure. Unlike middle class, they are smart enough to know that they are trapped, but not powerful enough to escape from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, what is the best then? If we could not become the upper class, should we be learn ignorance and be the most happy social class?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer is &lt;strong&gt;NO&lt;/strong&gt;. I present you the free being, the free being who are not bound by anything. To be free being , it would require the will to truth and will to power. The will to truth is the will to understand the truth of the condition they are in. Lower class need to will to know the truth behind the false hope which that are given to them. What come after is the ultimate will to power. Ultimate will to power, are to power over ourself. One who prioritize will to power over others are still bound by some constraint, like the politician or dictator. He who will to power over himself, are truly free from any constraint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, who is a lower class, finding out the truth behind the social construct should will to power over himself, stop trapping inside the trap with disguise of sensual pleasure. He, who is a middle class, should will to power over himself, stop getting deeper into the trap bury himself off with all the loans and borrowing. He, who is a upper class, should prioritize will to power over himself instead of will to power over others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;He cannot rule himself will certainty be ruled by others&quot;- Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ultimate free being, would not only free from the nature of constraint that would bound on them, also free from the constraint of being in any social construct itself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How similar social construct of 1984 is to ours</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/images/post/2018-07/1984.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Opinion] Programming Exam???</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/programming-exam/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Opinion] Programming Exam???" /><published>2018-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/programming-exam</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/programming-exam/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;programming-exam&quot;&gt;Programming Exam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a computer science or related field student, most likely you had came across programming exam that are closed book. On top of that, you are required to write you answer on paper instead of typing it into computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, what is programming?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Computer programming is a process that leads from an original formulation of a computing problem to executable computer programs.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, programming is writing code with following a set of rules and hence creating a computer programs that can be run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;writing-code-on-paper&quot;&gt;Writing code on paper&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to above definition, the end result of programming should be executable programs. Then, can writing code on paper result in an executable program?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In real world, when we perform programming, we write codes and run it. If our code had problem, error will arise and notify us in which line does the code had problem and what the problem is. We then debug from the error that given by the computer and solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However during the exam, we are unable to verify if error exists in our code and we will most likely to be punnished for it. If so, does the exam truly able to measure the learning outcome of the subject? It does not test programming skills of the student, but rather test the ability to memorize the syntax and rules of the language itself, which this will leads to our next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;close-book-exam&quot;&gt;Close book exam?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a fans of close book exam, more so for close book programming exam. Programming is not about memorizing all the syntax and rules of the language. In fact, these rules and syntax can easily be found in documentation. There is no point in memorizing them. In fact, if one practice enough for a particular programming language, he/she will be able to remember the syntax and rules of the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In real world, we are able to look for reference. Whatever we do not know, we can always Google search and look for books. It is so easy to find information that we do not know. If we are not allowed to search for information during the exam, the exam are testing one memorizing skills rather than understanding and searching skills, which is more important than memorizing. These type of exam does not truly able to measure the outcome of the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real problem come after that. Student forget whatever they memorize after the exam as if they had not learn the subject before. This is one of the major problem that create a gap between education and workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to programming exam, what more important for programming is the ability in looking for documentation and understanding the documentation. We need to understand how things work in order to be able to utilize them to solve various problem. Close book programming exam does not promote understanding, but rather memorizing of the solution. If the problem are changed, he/she who memorize without understanding it will be unable to solve the problem because the solution only fit to the specific problem. The exam outcome does not truly measure programming skills of student, but memorizing skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;am-i-trying-say-exam-should-not-exists&quot;&gt;Am I trying say exam should not exists?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I am not. Exam has it’s purpose, which is to measure the learning outcome of the period. There are other type of assessment such as assignments, test, project, etc. However, they are there for a different purpose. For assignment and project, we are able to ask for help from other people when problem arise. We always know the genius who we can ask for answer. However, there are cases where we will face situation where we do not had anyone to ask for help from. We need to be able to utilize whatever around us to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not saying that ask for help is bad. Ask for help is also a type of skills. Asking the right question will result in getting the answer we want meanwhile the opposite might not result the same. However, looking for answer by ourself are also an important skills to master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-solution&quot;&gt;My solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If current exam system are unable to achieve the purpose of having an exam, we should evolve the system itself. I think all exam should be open book and we should at least allowed to take reference from book if internet are not possible. We should be able to refer to reference material during exam, because reference material are meant to be refer, not memorize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the case of programming exam, we should be able to use computer and submit our answer digitally. It is understandable if internet are not allowed during the exam due to exchanging answer with using social media, but we should at least has access to offline documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this solution might not be perfect, but it is without a doubt solve some problem that we are having now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In real world, we are able to search for information when face with problem. However, exam does not allow that, Moreover, it promote the use of memorizing than understanding. Therefore, it create a gap between education system and workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, we should be allowed to make reference to reference material during the exam, and hence promote searching and understanding skills over memorizing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Things that gone wrong for most programming exam</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/images/post/2018-05/programming.jpg" /></entry></feed>