<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-21T15:43:29+08:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Ng Wei Shyang</title><subtitle>Just another Homo sapiens who are interested in life and death</subtitle><entry><title type="html">[Opinion] Useless Knowledge</title><link href="/blog/useless-knowledge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Opinion] Useless Knowledge" /><published>2019-04-21T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-04-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/useless-knowledge</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/useless-knowledge/">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me personally knows that I have a profound interest in philosophy, the same goes to this friend of mine who thinks that philosophy is useless. So, there is a day sometime in the past when he argues that philosophy is all about studying useless stuff and it does not help us with anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing that, I try to convince him about why despite philosophy might seems useless, philosophy is actually useful. I give out various argument such as how philosophy can be used as a hypothesis generator, how philosophy is the origin of logic which drives science, how philosophy can help us live a more enlightened life since we can only live once and you definitely do not want to ruin it, how philosophy can act as complementary tools together with psychology to build a better relationship, how political philosophy can be used to contribute to advancing our political institution, how philosophy can be used to identify logical fallacy given out by politician to win your votes, etc. After some discussion, we realize that our definition of philosophy is slightly different, and we begin to clarify it. It turns out that the part of philosophy that had been exposed to him are mostly related to social studies, and he thinks that social studies are absolutely useless which do not help you with anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I am not familiar with social studies, I’m declined to give my opinion on social studies. However, as I am a keen believer of no knowledge is useless, our discussion turns from “is philosophy useless” to “are there useless knowledge”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;knowledge-as-bullet-metaphor&quot;&gt;Knowledge as bullet metaphor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A metaphor I like to put it is the bullet metaphor I created. There are guns, and there are bullets. A particular type of bullet can be used in a range of guns, some have a wider range, while others have a narrower range. If bullets are knowledge we possess, a gun will be the practical implication of the knowledge we possess. What this essentially means is that obtaining a wide range of knowledge is like collecting a wide range of bullets. During the time of collection, the bullet might seem useless, but when there is one day where a gun appear which the bullet can be used, it is going to be more useful than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, some bullet has a more narrow range of gun which can be used and some guns are rarer than the others. The same goes for knowledge, where some knowledge is more useful than others. However, that does not dictate a knowledge being useless, but it simply means that the knowledge has a lower probability of being useful in one life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-guns-shoot-why-bother&quot;&gt;All guns shoot, why bother?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, all gun shoot, but we can say without a doubt that some guns perform better under certain circumstances than the others. Take a sniper, for example, it will without a doubt outperform a shotgun when it comes to long-range accuracy while shotgun will outperform a sniper in short-range damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine a person who is a shotgun specialist, collect nothing but shotgun’s bullets. Any shotgun that reaches his hand, most likely he will have the appropriate bullet for it. Translate to knowledge, this person is like someone who is a specialist in a particular narrow field. He will be able to nail it for any short-range target like how he able to answer any question from the specialize narrow field of his, anything more than a short-range will be most likely be in vain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, imagine a person who collects any type of bullet. Contrast it to the person we imagined earlier, he might not be able to nail it like how the former does, however, he will have a higher chance of doing the job when being put under most circumstances. This person, who collects any type of bullet, will most likely be a more successful hunter than the former as hunting involve not only short-range, long-range, but everything in between as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the person we imagined earlier is favored when it comes to a short-range shooting competition. The reason is simple. A person who collects nothing but shotgun’s bullets has a much higher probability when it comes to possessing the best bullet for a particular gun. An equivalent example would be like using a full metal jacket bullet instead of half metal jacket bullet in a penetration competition. In that competition, the guns are provided by the organizer, and a specialist will more likely to possess a full metal jacket bullet for the gun provided than a half/non-specialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the main reason when it comes to job or research, a specialist is favored compared to a non-specialist as a specialist is more likely to do a better job than otherwise. When I use the word specialist, I do not mean by someone who pursues a formal education in a particular field, but someone who has tremendous knowledge of a particular field, can either obtain either from formal education or non-formal education such as self-learning. Of course, being a specialist does not mean you can only possess knowledge from the field you specialize in, but also can learn anything from other fields as interest, or perhaps interest went too far (someone who from hobby become a specialist).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;physics-as-an-example&quot;&gt;Physics as an example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us take physics as an example. We all know that everything around our life is surround with physics. Our water supply, electric supply, electronic device, air-conditioner, car, and a lot more is the product of our physics understanding. It is the understanding of classical mechanics that allows water coming out from our water tap. It is the understanding of the electrical magnetism that allows the existence of our electric supply and not to mentions, any device that drives by electricity. It is the understanding of thermodynamics that allows air-conditioner to cool down our room. It is a piece of extremely useful knowledge, but we can get by with our life without a problem without any physics knowledge, especially in the world of specialization. It is the specialization that allows us to be able to get by our life without any understanding of physics theory. Someone else, can be as close as someone under the same rooftop, or as far as someone on the other side of the world, specializing in physics and helping us to improve our lives while we specialize on something else and improve their life in those aspects. It makes me does nothing but to wonder if does possessing physics knowledge for us as an individual who does not specialize in any field related to it does us good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you who possess anything more than a sensible amount of physics will be able to answer some of the practical implication of physics to an individual without a problem. The main reason, I believe, is due to having the experience of any physics knowledge possessed which comes in handy throughout daily life. Not only that, having the knowledge of physics will likely to provide an understanding of the implication of the knowledge itself too. I will further elaborate on this point in the next part of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a scenario, where a person is trying to build his/her own desktop. This person bought a computer case, case fan, and several other parts which are essential for a computer to works. Now, during the stage of assembly, this person had to decide how should he/she mount the fan and which one of them is supposed to be intake and exhaust. This person tries to google it but found him/herself to be more lost than before as different sources giving a different answer with a different justification. All of them make sense, which makes this person not being able to come to a final decision where it works best for him/her. If this person has some basic understanding of aerodynamics, this person will most likely not have any problem in deciding the best-suited configuration of the fan from all different sources, if this person needs to even “google” the question in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give another example, where a person has a faulty ballast in one of the lightings in his house. Now, he comes across with LED tube and finds no reason to replace the ballast, but migrating it to LED tube instead. He bought a LED tube, went home happily, and eventually find himself not knowing how to bypass the faulty ballast which he has. If he has some basic knowledge of electricity, he will most likely be able to understand the flow of electricity with little to no effort and be able to safely modify it to bypass the ballast without any problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, while a seemingly useful knowledge to humanity as a whole might not be required for an individual who has no professional relationship with it, it can be tremendously useful when situation arise where the possession of related knowledge can be utilized. Although physics might not be the best example which I can use, I think it is an example which most people can relate or understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;correlation-between-possessing-the-knowledge-and-understanding-its-implication&quot;&gt;Correlation between possessing the knowledge and understanding its implication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is sort of the further elaboration of the previous point. Previously, when I talk about the practical implication of physics to us as an individual whose profession has nothing to do with physics, I had mentioned that people with a reasonable amount of knowledge on it will most likely be able to give out some practical implication. This is my next point, which I realize there is a sort of positive correlation between depths of understanding of a subject with the probability of knowing the practical implication of it. I had not looked up any empirical data that support this, nor do I try to gather empirical proof about it, but there is a sort of logical explanation to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about understanding the implication, there are 2 different types of scenario. The first type of scenario is where the desire for knowledge is generated from the desire of achieving the goal implication. An example of it is one’s desire of living a happier life leads to the pursuit of life philosophy knowledge such as Stoicism, Epicureanism, etc. In this scenario, unless one has a desire to some ends, one will not even realize the implication of certain knowledge as one is not exposed to the implication in the very first place. It appears as a form of “if I know xxx, I will be able to xxx”. A lot of time, people without scientific knowledge and still be able to come up with practical implication of it falls into this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second type of category is where the knowledge is required to understand the implication in the very first place. Again, take political philosophy as an example, one does not even know the practical implication of political philosophy until one is exposed to it, which is to make the best logical decision when it comes to deciding which candidates to vote. Without the knowledge of it, one will most likely think that he can make the best decision without it as he knows what is best for him. This is a part of “Dunning-Kruger effect”, but that is a topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there is no clear separation on what kind of knowledge belongs to which category, however, if one does not come across a scenario which belongs to the former category, one will not be able to understand the implication of that particular knowledge without understanding it. It is until one tries to look into that knowledge, one will realize there is more implication than one can ever think of. This is also the main reason why I decline to accept my friend’s stance on social studies while refusing to defend it either as I do not understand the implication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;putting-it-all-together&quot;&gt;Putting it all together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum it all up, knowledge is exactly like a bullet. You might not know what kind of gun you can use a bullet on, but when you have the gun, it will be extremely useful. For knowledge, it is the same. You might not know what is the use of a particular knowledge for a particular time, it can be very useful if circumstances arise when the knowledge is required. However, the main dilemma should be there is so many knowledge, and there are only 24 hours per day, reduce the time we work, travel, eat, shower, and etc, it is only the rest of the time where we can use it to learn some extra knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, ultimately, curiosity is a part of human nature, and to have an interest in a certain knowledge should be the goal itself instead of being the means to some end. Otherwise, what is the purpose of life without any interest?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Is there any useless knowledge in the world?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-04/useless-knowledge.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Opinion] Greed as human vice</title><link href="/blog/greed-is-no-evil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Opinion] Greed as human vice" /><published>2019-04-07T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-04-07T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/greed-is-no-evil</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/greed-is-no-evil/">&lt;p&gt;Greed is human behavior that had been regarded as vices since a long past history of civilization. Seven deadly sins, teaching from Christianity, lay out the seven vices behavior, namely pride, greed, lust, envy, gluttony, wrath, and sloth. Greed is one of those among them. Aside from Christianity, many other religions such as Buddhism, Hinduism, Islam, and many others also have a similar stance against greed. However, despite greed being widely regarded as a vice, is it actually something that is so evil?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;basic-need-basic-wants-and-overly-wants&quot;&gt;Basic need, basic wants, and overly wants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start discussing greed, we need to understand what is the exact definition of greed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Greed is an excessive desire to possess wealth or goods with the intention to keep it for one's self.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above definition are taken from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greed_(disambiguation)&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. In the above definition, it uses &lt;em&gt;excessive desire&lt;/em&gt; to distinguish what is considered as greed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the use of &lt;em&gt;desire&lt;/em&gt; indicates wants, which is by itself different from needs. While there is a general guideline of what’s considered as need, but there are many scenarios where it is extremely ambiguous to decide which side should it belongs to. Take a smartphone as an example, while it does not directly affect one’s survival, it can indirectly heavily affect one’s survival in a city where a lot of activities involve smartphones. A job can be one of those activities, where it is extremely difficult for one to find a job without a smartphone. Without a job, one will not have an income, which affects one’s ability to sustain himself. You might argue that there are a lot of jobs where it does not require a smartphone, and human had lived their life without a smartphone for the past thousands, if not million years, up until the last century when smartphones are widespread to the majority of the people, which makes it a wants. Therefore, it is extremely difficult to classify them to either one category. However, the good news is even if a smartphone is considered as wants, desire for a smartphone will never be considered as greed because desires for a smartphone is clearly not overly wants, which brings us to the next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of &lt;em&gt;excessive desire&lt;/em&gt; in the definition indicates overly wants, which is different from basic wants. Generally, we will consider things like desires for a smartphone or a car as basic wants while desires for a 500 thousand square feet bungalow or a big car garage full of supercar would be classified as overly wants. The main way we draw a line between basic wants and overly wants is the former is able to provide a huge increase in happiness with a relatively small amount of cost compare to the gain while the latter involves a large amount of cost in exchange for a relatively small amount of happiness increase. Again, the same problem exists when it comes to distinguishing basic wants and overly wants. For some people, desires for a Mercedes-Benz car is basic wants, while it is overly wants for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it is extremely difficult to distinguish them, for this blog, we will assume that we are able to distinguish them because actually distinguishing them is a whole topic of another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-world-without-greed&quot;&gt;A world without greed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider a world without greed, it is going to be a world where very little improvement happens from our day to day life. Thousands of technologies we enjoy today is also impossible. This is because needs, basic wants and overly wants changes from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider around 200-300 years ago, where the majority of peoples do not have a private toilet in their house, a private toilet is almost an overly wants according to that period standards. If we date back to earlier than that, toilet sear does not exist, and the toilet is merely a hole. It is the vision of some people for an improved standard of living, they envision a world where private toilet exists in every house, and a toilet bowl for every given toilet. Today, we would consider such desire merely needs. Potentially, it is considered as basic wants for people hundreds of years ago, and nevertheless overly wants for any time period earlier than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us consider another situation, where to imagine having a handheld size machinery that can perform various calculation within a fraction of milliseconds is impossible, and having such desire is nothing but both overly wants and daydreaming. Today, not only our 13 inches laptop that can achieve it, such can even be achieved with something as small as a smartwatch. It is because of someone laziness of calculating with various calculation tools in the past, the calculator is invented, and it changes our lives tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let us put someone genuine desire to improve the human standard of living aside, let’s imagine a person who desires is to live a life where he/she can buy anything without thinking twice, be able to live in a huge bungalow, and owns numerous supercar. What is the best way for this person to achieve what he/she desires? The best way to achieve that is to be a successful entrepreneur. To be a successful entrepreneur, he/she is required to be able to build a successful business that outperforms the competitors, and the only ways to outperform the competitor is to innovate. You may think that innovation is not required and the best way is to merge with competitors and create a monopoly. However, by doing so, there will always be new competitors appears so long as it is a free market, and it will not be a long term solution. This person, so desperate to be rich, trying out numerous idea, trying to innovate every single day, and eventually, not only he achieve the lifestyle he wants to live, the innovation that brings by this person also advance the society forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A world without greed, everyone is content with what they have, there will no longer be an improvement, not in science, not in literature, not in art, neither does it in technology. A world without greed, talking to your friend millions of miles away is impossible because people are content with being able to only communicate with people when they meet physically. A world without greed, we will still be a hunter-gatherer tribe because our ancestor does not bother with having a fixed shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drawing-a-line&quot;&gt;Drawing a line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greed had always been the guiding force towards human advancement. However, at the very same time, greed had also destroyed countless people’s lives. Greed, while being used in a good way, positively affect human’s life. On the contrary, misuse of greed would lead to disaster.  This is also the main reason why greed is generally being regarded as bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason greed is highly regarded as evil, I believe, is due to the cognitive bias of a person towards the subject. In general, when greed does not affect us, we do not pay extra attention to the subject. However, when it does affect us, we pay extra attention and put extra weight on the negative effect of greed. This is how we slowly build up the general perception of greed is evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly, a line needs to be drawn so we can stay within the good boundary of greed and do not goes beyond it. An example of greed going beyond control would be Elizabeth Anne Holmes from Theranos. She started the company, wanting to become rich by revolutionalize how a blood test is carried out. However, as she working towards the vision, she faces various obstacles, and her pride does not allow her to step back and admit these obstacles she facing to the investors and public. Deception and manipulation are used in order to let her stay in her position. In the end, it not only affects her investor, but it also put people who perform blood test with her solution at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If she declares the actual results of her company to the investors and the public, trying hard to raise more funds without giving false results, the difficulty in raising funds might increase, and the business might fail eventually (which she fails nevertheless, making it a zero lost decision), she would had most likely goes on to the next business with her ability, very likely to become rich eventually, meanwhile benefiting humanity with the innovation ideas that brought by her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while greed might bring positive effect, we should always be aware that we should not be blinded by greed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Is greed actually a vice of human behavior?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-03/greed.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[意見] 探討人類的惡性主要之一：貪婪</title><link href="/blog/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC%E8%B2%AA%E5%A9%AA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[意見] 探討人類的惡性主要之一：貪婪" /><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC%E8%B2%AA%E5%A9%AA</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC%E8%B2%AA%E5%A9%AA/">&lt;p&gt;從古至今，貪婪被大衆人類視爲人性最醜陋之一。在基督教的教導裏擁有七項人類必須避開的惡性，叫作七宗罪；他們分別於傲慢，貪婪，色慾，妒忌，暴食，憤怒和怠惰。我們今天要談論的課題：貪婪，列在七宗罪的其中之一。除了基督教以外，很多的其他宗教都擁有類似的教導；這包括基督教，伊斯蘭教，等等。我們今天探討的問題是貪婪真的有如自古以來被大衆認知的如此邪惡嗎？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;沒有貪婪的世界&quot;&gt;沒有貪婪的世界&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;貪婪指的是一種攫取遠超於自身需求的資源，可以是金錢，物質或其他的慾望。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;當我們說一個人自身的需求，一個人自身的需求會隨着時間的流去而改變。在一個還沒有文明社會的世界是，一個人的需求也不過與一個能夠作爲住宿的地方和足夠補充個人能量的食物。大約兩千年前，個人需要再也不只是住宿與食物，它也被擴充到穿着。現今，即使手提電話也成爲了一個人的基本需求。個人基本需求是一項無比難於限定的東西。它隨着時間的改變。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;這帶到了我今天的第一個論點，也就是貪婪是造成個人需求改變的原因之一。爲什麼我這麼說呢？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;試想想，在大約200-300年前，所謂的廁所也只不過是在一些有土地挖了一個洞，並且稱他爲廁所。絕大部分的野外露營也都還在用同一個方法來解決排泄物。因爲人們對此不滿意，決定發明了一個叫做馬桶的東西，並且大大的提升了人類的衛生素質。擁有了此發明，人們的衛生需求也逐漸的提升，每個住宿裏擁有一個衛生間也變成了一個基本需求。整個過程的導火線也是因人類的貪婪，不滿意當時的需要，並且想要擁有更好的措施。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;沒有貪婪的世界，每一個人都滿足了當下擁有的東西，任何的進步也不會發生。在獵人收集者的時代，如果人們沒有想要一個更加穩定的食物供給的來源，人類將不會開始試圖種植，更不會在現今試圖想盡辦法的提高種植參量。諾古人不在乎使用心算來計算任何數學的問題，算盤，計算機，電腦以及其他用來協助計算的工具也不會被發明。試想如果人們沒有想要把生產過程自動化以及工業化，工業革命也不會發生，我們現今也無法享受到了我們現今所能享受到的物質便利了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;貪婪好的一面&quot;&gt;貪婪好的一面&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;因爲貪婪，我們擁有了各種各樣的科學進步。也因爲貪婪，我們的文明不斷試圖拖進經濟發展，並且隨着時間的流動慢慢的提高了我們的生活素質。貪婪是絕大部分發展中的推動力以及導火線。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我們以上所談到的是貪婪對人類身爲一個集體帶來的好處。可能，你有可能認爲太廣闊了，並且對身爲一個個體的你不是很有關聯，那麼我們來談談關於貪婪對身爲一個個體的我們又帶來了什麼好處。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;身爲一個個體的我們，如果貪婪完全不存在，攝取知識的動力也將不存在。我們攝取知識主要的推動力是有望攝取到的知識在未來可以讓我們過得更輕鬆。這個可以在很多不同的形式下呈現，包括我們青年時到小，中和大學上課，以便得來的文憑可以用以建立事業。再舉出另一個例子，我們在校外自行自學一門學問，心理學打個比方，是有望這一門學問在未來可以幫助我們更好的建立與維持人際關係。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;以上，無論是建立事業或者是維持人際關係，雙方的基本動機都是爲了擁有更良好的生活素質；它既不是個人的基本需求，而是滿足個人的貪婪。沒有了貪婪就沒有了攝取知識的動機，也就沒有了建立良好事業的動機，一來也就無法讓家人過上較好的生活。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;貪婪的接線&quot;&gt;貪婪的接線&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;自然，貪婪被絕大部分人歸類爲惡性並不是沒有原因。適量的貪婪不但可以推進人類的進展，也可以幫助個體過上更好的生活素質。可是，當一個人使用貪婪的時候，這一個人也必須直覺到分離好與壞的貪婪的接線。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;當過度的貪婪導致把自己貪婪的代價放到了別人身上時，他也就變成了一個惡性。很好的例子將會是血測公司「Theranos」的創辦人伊莉莎白·霍姆斯（Elizabeth Anne Holmes）。一開始，霍姆斯只不過是一個想要成功創業的年輕了，擁有一個想要改變整個驗血過程的夢想。開始創業後，因爲重重的挫折阻止她的夢想成真，卻已經擁有了不少的投資者，且放不下她的自豪心，只好一次再一次的欺騙大衆以及投資者。紙包不住火，各種詐騙到最後也被揭曉出來，而她也一落千丈。這起案件的受害者不僅僅是該公司的投資者，其中也包括了前往使用該公司驗血設施的測驗者，以及該公司的員工。這一切的起源僅僅是一個人的貪婪以及自豪心。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;終結&quot;&gt;終結&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;貪婪之所以被大衆認爲是人類的噁心並不是沒有原因。該認知來歷於大衆的認知偏見。當一個人善用貪婪，爲他自己創造了對他來說最好的生活時，因爲沒有影響到任何的人，沒有人爲其所關注。但是，當一個人擁有能夠傷害到他人的貪婪時，因爲該貪婪對其他人照成了麻煩，所以被他人所關注，並且把貪婪這個行爲歸類爲惡性。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以，貪婪並非惡，而惡在於該貪婪如何被使用。明白了這些，我們應該在使用貪婪的時候更加的謹慎以便在獲得其中好處的同時，也避免獲得其中的壞處。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;另加編輯&quot;&gt;另加編輯&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;當我把這篇文章發出去後，我的其中一個朋友像我提出關於雖然以上所提出的論點都很公平，可是他另加了在慾望裏，其中也需要提出關於基本慾望以及過度慾望。在他們的區別中，前者是一些比較基本的慾望，比如擁有一間舒適的住家，擁有一個不錯的車，等等。另一方，過度慾望將會是想要擁有500千平方英尺的豪宅，一個擁有數輛輛超跑的車庫，等等。他們的區別基本上是前者能夠對一個人產生很大的生活素質改變，後者反而對一個人不會有很大的生活改變。拿回以上車庫的例子，一個擁有非常多超跑車庫的車主擁有非常大可能性不會使用到那些的車。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我的朋友便提到以上的論點都非常的傾向基本慾望，而大部分人不把基本慾望歸類爲貪婪，而是過有慾望。這也是我要在這裏澄清的事項。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;首先，基本慾望以及過有慾望的確有他們的不同之處，而問題出現在劃分基本慾望以及過有慾望的界線。基本慾望以及過有慾望是非常困難劃分的，因爲不同人擁有不同的基本慾望以及過有慾望的定義。打個比方，大部分人可能認爲一輛車是基本慾望，擁有一車庫的超跑是過有慾望，那麼擁有一輛奔馳房車到底應該被歸類成前者或是後者呢？我個人雖然可能認爲他應該被歸類爲前者，可是也有很多人把他歸類爲後者，這也尤其是一些比較愤世嫉俗的人。這一些人認爲他們做工那麼的辛苦卻不獲得他所應得的補償，老闆一人卻獲得了全部的回報買新家和換奔馳，難道就不能買便宜一點的車，把那些剩下的錢來回報員工嗎？對於我個人來說，這位老闆在成功之前拿了多麼高的風險來創業，這一切也是這位老闆所應得的回報。另外，這些人也沒有想過他們到底值不值得獲得更高的報酬，每天只想着老闆獲得的錢他就應該被分多一些。所以，劃分基本慾望以及過度慾望是非常苦難的事情。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;另外，假設我們真的可以劃分基本慾望以及過度慾望，我以上所舉出的論點也可以應用在過度慾望之上。當一個個體擁有所謂的過度慾望，只要這個個體能夠劃分貪婪好壞的接線，使用不牽涉別人的方法來滿足該慾望，這個過度慾望不僅僅會爲這個個人帶了同樣的好處，也會爲社會爲一個集體帶來好處。我們再拿回以上所提到的例子，即使伊莉莎白·霍姆斯擁有過度慾望，想要創業成功成爲富豪，如果她向投資者澄清她所理想的驗血法式並非可能，並且轉移注意力到了下一個創業，她不僅僅前途可望，有朝一日她成功時，她爲了滿足慾望對社會所帶來的革新主義可是益處無窮。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以，無論是基本慾望或是過有慾望，只要使用正確手段達成該個體的貪婪，貪婪依然並非惡性。反而，即使是基本慾望，諾爲達成基本慾望使用了負面影響其他人的手段，該貪婪依然被歸類爲惡性。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">衆所周知人類的惡性之一擁有如此的惡劣嗎？</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-03/greed.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Anime] Murder vs Slaughter</title><link href="/blog/muder-vs-slaughter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Anime] Murder vs Slaughter" /><published>2019-03-16T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/muder-vs-slaughter</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/muder-vs-slaughter/">&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I watch an Anime series call 空の境界 (Kara no Kyoukai). In the 7th movie of the series, it discusses an interesting concept, which is the differences between the word 殺人 and 殺戮.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;殺人 &lt;em&gt;(Japanese)&lt;/em&gt;，pronounce as &lt;em&gt;satsujin&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;さつじん&lt;/em&gt; in hiragana, can be translated to murder in general. 殺戮 &lt;em&gt;(Japanese)&lt;/em&gt;, on the other hand, pronounce as &lt;em&gt;satsuriku&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;さつりく&lt;/em&gt; in hiragana, generally can be translated to slaughter. Both 殺人 and 殺戮 are subject to different interpretation while referring to a different source. For the Japanese interpretation of it, we will only look at the definition defined by the author of Kara no Kyoukai, Kinoko Nasu in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;definition-of-slaughter-and-murder-by-nasu-in-japanese-sense&quot;&gt;Definition of slaughter and murder by Nasu in japanese sense&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the movie, Nasu differentiates murder and slaughter to the matter of if human dignity is on the stake. To qualify as murder, human dignity had to be present on both parties involved. This can be interpreted as the murderer while murdering the victim, he has to see his victim as a human being, while the victim also has to have fear of death present. Any one side of human dignity is not present, it will no longer be qualified as murder, but slaughter instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;It only becomes murder when people put their dignity and their past on a scale and eliminate one. Then you bear the significance and the sin of killing someone. But slaughter is different. The one who was killed is human, but the one who killed lacks the dignity of a human and is no longer human.&quot; ― Touko Aozaki&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of slaughter, despite the human dignity of the victim present, the slaughterer no longer views the victim as a human being, something that has little to no value in their life. Therefore, the quote by Shiki’s grandfather is being reiterated over and over again in the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;A person can only kill one person in their lifetime.&quot; ― Shiki's grandfather&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because, when one kill someone once, the next time he/she kill someone else, it will no longer be the same as if when he/she kill for the first time, and he/she will view the victim as lesser a human, until he/she so get used to killing someone that he no longer view his victim as a human being anymore. Therefore, any killing subsequent to the first killing will be classified as slaughter according to Nasu’s definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is completely possible that one who exists never get to experience murder, where the person in question does not view his victim as a human being from the first time. But, those are the very rare case, and it also does not contradict with the quote by Shiki’s grandfather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;standard-definition-of-slaughter-and-murder-in-english&quot;&gt;Standard definition of slaughter and murder in English&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In English, the standard definition distinct both words down to a matter of numbers. Murder defines when a person kill another person (it can be single victim or multiple victims, but the rule is there cannot be too many victims, though many are relative and subjective, we might use murder on a case where there are 2 victims, but we don’t usually do the same when there are 5 victims or above, and anything in between will not be discussed here) while slaughter defines when a person kills many people. To qualify as murder, all it needs to be is there is a single or very little victims. A serial murderer is someone who every time when he carries out his murder, he do not kill many persons at a time, but kill little by little over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, to qualify as murder, the prior experience of a murderer, intentions, how he views the victims and whether human dignity is on stake is not taken into consideration. A serial murderer can carry out 10 cases of murder prior to the 11th incident, while the said incident still qualifies as murder as long as he does not kill a large number of peoples in the 11th incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, to qualify as slaughter, all it needs is multiple victims in a single incident. The slaughterer can be a first timer, has his human dignity on the stake, seeing his victims as a human being and still qualify as a slaughterer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To best demonstrate this, it will be a school shooting carried out by a victim of school bullying. The school shooting happens because the school shooter’s emotion towards the bullier exceeds his/her capacity and his/her human dignity is on the stake when carrying out the school shooting, yet it qualified as slaughter merely because there are many victims in that incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deontology-vs-consequentialism&quot;&gt;Deontology vs Consequentialism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both definitions being discussed above differentiate murder and slaughter as a way of defining the scale of immorality. In a scale of morality, where left is moral and right is immoral, murder will be left in relative to slaughter. The only differences here is the method of measuring them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Nasu context, it adopts deontological morality. Deontology is a theory that measures morality/ethics of action by whether the action itself is right or wrong. In his definition, an incident qualifies as murder when both parties involved have their human dignity on stake. By having human dignity on stake when an incident happens, it classifies as more towards the left on a scale of immorality compared to another incident where the killer slaughtering other humans like a machine. This is because the former only happens when the killer’s emotion exceed his/her capacity, and he/she has more emotional margin in making a rational decision of whether to carrying out the murder or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In standard definition in English, it adopts consequentialism. Consequentialism is a theory where it measures morality/ethics of an action by the consequences. When judging by definition, killing a person is far worse than not killing anyone, and killing 10 is far worse than killing a person. Therefore, an incident with lesser victims is on the less severe scale of immoral, hence murder, and an incident with multiple victims put it on a more severe scale of immoral, hence slaughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-the-definition-of-words-to-the-moral-system&quot;&gt;From the definition of words to the moral system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard definition of 殺人 and 殺戮 is difficult to find, and several online discussions on the topic also asserting the same. It is very similar to the case when a philosopher discusses suicide, throwing their own definition and understanding on it, and list out scenarios where it fits into the definition but would normally not had thought to be suicide and further examine on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we can safely assume that there are many people who use the same language with Nasu has the same definition as him on both the words 殺人 and 殺戮. If that is not the case, Nasu will most likely not have the definition in the first place as he is not the creator of the word and the construction on the understanding of words are normally from the influence of others throughout one’s daily interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give an example on the above point, think about the definition of the word game. We had never been told the definition of game, but when we are given a list, we somehow know if the item within the list is a game. Wittgenstein once explores in his book Philosophical Investigations, that it is impossible to give a perfect definition of the word game. Our purpose today is not to conclude if is it possible to give a perfect definition to the word, but the reason why we somehow know if something is a game is due to our construction of the meaning of game throughout daily interaction with others. The same happens to Nasu when it comes to him constructing the definition of both 殺人 and 殺戮.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it commonly understood 殺人 and 殺戮 as a distinction of the severity of immorality, the definition given reflects the moral system adopted by the culture which the language originated from. Perhaps, in Japanese culture, deontology is more widely adopted than consequentialism while the otherwise are more widely adopted in western culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;language-influence-moral-system&quot;&gt;Language influence moral system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the definition of words might reflect the moral system adopted within a culture, the opposite might be true too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for us to be able to imagine a concept, it does not necessarily require the language counterpart to exist, but it makes imagining the concepts extremely difficult, more so when communicating the concepts, which eventually get lost before being able to communicate to others. For instance, freedom is a concept that defines a condition without any constraint, and the word constraint is yet another concept which defines the limitation or restriction, which both the word limitation and restriction is yet another concepts. Without the language counterpart to the concept freedom, one can imagine it when one is being imprisoned, yet it is almost impossible for one to communicate the concepts freedom to others, let alone a philosophical movement for the said concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, because language can shape how we think, Japanese language users are more likely to adopt deontology while English language users are more likely to adopt consequentialism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-whats-the-answer&quot;&gt;So, what’s the answer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe, in the beginning, there consist of more people who adopt deontology in the group who created the Japanese language, and more people who adopt consequentialism within the group who created the English language. Because of that, it shapes the language in a way that is more likely to influence people to be of the same kind. After that, the very same group of people, because there are more likely to adopt one moral system, they further created more words which are more likely to influence people to be the same kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, it is Nasu who made up the definition to makes the anime interesting. Maybe, there isn’t anyone in Japan besides Nasu who use those words the way he use it. Potentially, the standard definition of 殺人 and 殺戮 in Japanese is no different from the standard definition of murder and slaughter in English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, the theory is all wrong together. It is the creator of the word who is the one that adopt deontology or consequentialism, and language might be able to shape people’s thinking but can’t shape people moral system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">From distinction of words to moral perception</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-03/murder.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Opinion] Is Tax Escape Right?</title><link href="/blog/tax-escape/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Opinion] Is Tax Escape Right?" /><published>2019-03-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-03-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/tax-escape</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/tax-escape/">&lt;p&gt;If your preferred language is chinese, visit &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC%E9%80%83%E7%A8%85/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for the chinese version of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;foreword&quot;&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several days ago, there is a meetup with my friends from high school. In meetup, I have a small discussion with one of my friend who is currently pursuing an accounting degree about future career plans. During the discussion, she told me that she is taking a professional paper, and it is extremely difficult, especially for her, who do not have any prior experience in accounting fields. So, I ask her about why does she not take any accounting part-time during any of her sem break. Her answer to that question is she hate accounting, so she wanted to delay the time she works in accounting fields and would prefer to enjoy working on other part-time jobs such as promoter or cashier during sem break instead of accounting part-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, accounting degree holders are not limited to just accounting fields, but can also pursue a career in banking, finance, and a lot more. So I ask her if she ever considers pursuing a career in any other fields besides accounting. She then told me that she is not interested in banking or finance, but is more interested in both business law or tax. This is where the idea of this blog comes from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we think of tax, naturally we think of how can we reduce the amount of taxes we need to pay, and tax escape is one of them. One of the most popular career to pursue that are related to tax is tax consultancy, and there is a high probability of a tax consultant involved in tax escape. This can come in the form of company consultancy scope of client offline request, and meanwhile, the legitimacy of a company might be able to avoid the former, the latter is irrelevant to the legitimacy of the company one working in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thought at that time is that there is nothing wrong with tax escape since one does not harm anyone during the process, except it’s a requirement from the government, and a law is a completely different thing from moral all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that night, while lying on the bed trying to sleep, I started thinking about this question, and I had come to my own conclusion to the question, which is what I am going to discuss here today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax, by definition, is a compulsory contribution to state revenue, levied by the government on workers’ income and business profits, or added to the cost of some goods, services, and transactions. The question here is what rights do a government have for taxing workers’ income, business profits or added cost of goods and services. In order to discuss that, we need to first discuss how would a world where a government does not exist looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;state-of-nature&quot;&gt;State Of Nature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State of nature is a world where no higher hierarchy and authorities exist. In a state of nature, governments do not exist, neither do mayor, army, police, village head or any form of authorities. So, what will state of nature looks like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Thomas Hobbes school of thought, in the state of nature, everyone has every right to everything, that which include the right to kill, the right to imprison, the right to rape, etc. Take murder, for example, the murderer is not unjust as he is merely exercising his right, neither does the victim is just, as justice does not exist in a state of nature. If one has to find just in a state of nature, it would be might. These lead to the famous quote of Thomas Hobbes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;No arts; no letters; no society; and which is worst of all, continual fear and danger of violent death; and the life of man, solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short.&quot; ― Thomas Hobbes&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there are east, there will be west. when there are good, there will be evil. When there is Thomas Hobbes school of thought, there will be Jean-Jacques Rousseau school of thought. Rousseau started with imagining a scenario where you and your friend went on to a sea trip. Somehow, some kind of accident leads you and your friends to a deserted island. There, on a deserted island, no higher authority exists, which resemble the state of nature. Would you start killing each other among your friend, or will you cooperate with each other, trying to find a way out of the deserted island? I believe most of us will choose the latter as it increases our chance of survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, he gives another hypothetical scenario, where there are two hunters in a jungle trying to hunt for animals, rabbit in this scenario. One day, when both of them out for hunting, they met each other. Now, they have two choices, first which is to cooperate with each other so that they can hunt down bigger prey, or they can fight with each other, chasing each other out of their “hunting ground”. If you are one of the hunters, would you go for former or latter? Most of us would say former, because by cooperating, not only we did not lose our original benefits, we gain extra benefits on top of it as it is a positive sum game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These hypothetical scenarios are where Rousseau conclude that in a state of nature, people will cooperate with each other, and it is the best state where a human can be in. However, these hypothetical scenarios have the assumption where people involved knows the benefit of cooperating with each other, and the very same hypothetical scenario is given to us, who are conditioned to live in a civilized society since born. With that assumption, we cannot conclude what kind of action would a person take when given to be in a state of nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, unlike both the political philosophers mention above, we now live in Post-Darwin era, and we have the evolution theory, where we know that evolution happens through the natural selection. Today, we know the most basic objective of living things, which is will for survival. Maybe, and just maybe, Rousseau is right, because by cooperating with each other, it increases the chances of survival, which all of us will choose if we would have been in a state of nature and even if we are not to be conditioned by civilization since born. But, throughout history, any form of tribes or hunter-gatherer always has warred with each other. For this, we need to look at the 3 main motivation for violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first 2 motivations are tightly related to the chances of survival. The first motivation for violence is self-defense. One uses violence for self-defense when facing violence imposed by other people, hoping to be able to survive from it. The second motivation for violence is to use violence in order to avoid being imposed on violence from other peoples. These 2 motivations are the main motivation that motivates most tribes or hunter-gatherer to exercise violence when their chances of survival are still low. So, although in the state of nature, chances of survival might increase for every person one cooperate with, there will be a point where it no longer increases the chances of survival for every extra person one cooperate with, and it might even decrease the chances of survival as more people might results in more conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, when one collective increase their chances of survival so much to the point where chances of survival are no longer taken into consideration of making choices, this will brings to the third motivation of violence, which is glory. Take a relatively big civilization, for example, perhaps with a population size of millions, chances that they are stable to a point where they no longer need to think about survival all day long are very high, and survival will no longer be the sole motivation behind every decision. Survival might still be the motivation behind starting some of the wars, the rest is for glory. To explain this, we need to look into theories that attempt to explain human behavior which we are aware of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 major theories in total, the first being discussed above, which is will to survival from Darwin. The remaining 3 are will to power from Nietzsche, will to meaning from Franklyn and will to happiness. Every single human behavior, as far as I know of, can fit into one or more of these theories, and glory potentially belongs to all 3 besides will to survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if there is one thing which we can conclude, it is going to be that the state of nature, regardless of how it actually looks like, will not be able to run away from violence. This brings us to the next section, which is the role of government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;social-contract&quot;&gt;Social contract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a state of nature, everyone has every right to everything, and there are a lot of rights which will bring undesired outcome, which includes rights of imprisonment, rape, steal, kill, etc. Since these are deemed undesired by most people, and avoidance from the undesired outcome from the rights are more important than having the rights itself, this is where the function of a social contract comes in. A social contract is created when a group of people comes together, give up a certain part of their rights in order to gain protection from having other people exercising the rights. These rights that had given up will be transferred to the body which governs the social contract, in most cases, the government, and the peoples who the social contract are applied to is a citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the question of what are the rights that most people willings to give up in order to get the respective benefit of it, it had been discussed for centuries by various political philosophers, and each of them has a different version of it. However, there are certain rights which are very obvious to which most of us are willings to give up in exchange for its benefit, which is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give up the rights of violence in exchange for social peace&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give up the rights of steal and rob in exchange for property rights&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give up the rights of rape and murder in exchange for protection from it&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These rights that had given up by us naturally are transferred to the government and the government can exercise these rights in the event when someone violated the rights which they do not have in order to ensure the rule-abiding citizens who had given up their rights receive their respective benefits. The exercising of these rights can come in the form of imprisonment, interrogate, torture, whip punishment, death sentence, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate it, let’s take the hypothetical scenarios created by Rousseau. An accident happens when your friend and you went on to a sea trip and ended up on a deserted island. Everyone worries about the other 6 misbehave, so all of you came to the agreement of the list of things which everyone is refrain from doing it, and if anyone violates the list, the person in question will be killed by the rest of the people. Here, since there are only 7 persons involve, it is manageable. So, all of you started a new life on the island and everything went smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few days after that, an accident happens on a large cruise ship not too far away from the deserted island which resides all 7 of you. On the cruise ship, there are more than 6000 passengers, but only 1500 made their way to the deserted island which you reside. Now, the population on the island had increased from 7 to 1507. Everyone on the island now had a town hall meeting, except it isn’t in a town hall but at the side of the beach, and everyone had again come to a new and more sophisticated list of things which one refrains from doing it and each of their consequences, instead of just killing off the offender. It is all good and nice, except a population of 1507 is no longer manageable with the previous way of managing it. So, all of you had decided to pick 100 strongest person out of the population to be the “police” who collectively assume the responsibility of the government and ensure the rule of law are put in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, without any benefits, these 100 strongest people would not carry out their job. They do not have the obligation to do so. So, the rest 1407 of the population yet again come to another agreement where every one of you will sacrifice one day worth of your production per month to a pool where it will be equally distributed to those 100 people. These 100 persons agree with the deal, and they now have the obligation to ensure the rule of law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one day worth of production which contribute to the pool is precisely tax. To the question of why they decide it to be one day worth of production instead of a fixed amount, says, 10 coconuts, is because, within the rule, one refrain from stealing from others, and it requires much more manpower to ensure one’s 1000 coconuts to not stolen by others than one’s 5 coconuts to not be stolen by others. Naturally, it is fair that one pay more when one receive more benefits, in this case, the manpower which ensures one’s property right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, understanding all these, what does it mean for tax evasion, or in the above hypothetical scenario, secretly not paying his worth of coconuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tax-evasion&quot;&gt;Tax Evasion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above, we had reached the conclusion that tax is a form of payment in order to ensure the benefits in exchange for the rights we had given up. Without it, the organization that assumes the responsibility will fall apart, and when it falls apart, nothing can ensure the rule of law, and one will no longer receive any benefit upon giving up the rights. Eventually, it will go back to the state of nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, tax evasion essentially means putting the cost of one receiving the benefits from rule of law onto others. Allow me to elaborate on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organization that assumes the responsibility to ensure the rule of law, in this case, the government, has the minimum cost required for operation. Take the 100 strongest people in the deserted island, the minimum cost, in that scenario, will be the resources required in order to meet their basic needs. Basic needs vary from time to time, depending on a lot of different factors, and it will not be discussed here, but we will simply assume food, shelter, and a seat on the ship which they are building for escaping the deserted island. Initially, those 1507 peoples on the island had come to the agreement to contribute one’s one day worth of production to a pool for sustaining the government (from now on we will call the 100 strongest people government) because when everyone pays their one day worth of production, it is sufficient to sustain the government. Everyone is happy for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a few weeks after that, a small group of people stops contributing their portion of resources into the pool. Soon, the pool running low in resources, and it no longer able to sustain the 100 persons, which leads to them not as motivated as ever before. Realizing this problem, everyone gathers and have another town hall meeting. By the end of the meeting, they had again came to the new agreement, which is to contribute one and a half day worth of production into the pool every month. Slowly, more and more people stop paying their worth of resources, and the whole loop happens all over again. Clearly, those people who had successfully escape from contributing their worth of resources had shifted their portion of the contribution to those who continue contributing their production to the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, tax evasion is wrong because it means wanting to enjoy the benefits without exchanging what it requires to sacrifice. Equivalent exchange is the foundation everything, and to deny it is to deny the value of everything in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;counterargument&quot;&gt;Counterargument&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you may think, what if it is not only the small group of people who stop paying their worth of contribution that leads to the lack of resources for maintaining the government, but it’s also among the 100 people who steal and misuse the resources in the pool. In that case, wouldn’t continue contributing to the pools simply means to helps those corrupted people in corruption?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that question, people who will misuse their power will misuse their power regardless of if you contribute to the pool or not. What one should do is to contribute to the pool so as not to shift one’s portion of the contribution to other peoples, and carry out other parts of one’s responsibility in the society, which is to think about the solution to the problem, work with the government to solve it, and overthrow the government if they are too corrupted. To translate that to the real world action, it can be participating in any anti-corruption political movement, contributing to related discussions in solving the issues, actually running for a position in the government so to change it from the inside, vote during the election, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one might also argue that there is fundamentally nothing wrong with tax evasion. What’s wrong with shifting one’s portion of the contribution to others when in nature, might is justice. Might, in this case, will be one’s resources required to successfully perform tax evasion in the very first place. It can come in the form of tax consultation fees, human resources, etc. Might is justice, and therefore, there is nothing wrong in shifting one’s contribution to other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to this argument is extremely simple. When one escape from paying tax, naturally the person in question also give up his benefits exchanged from paying the tax, and there will also be nothing wrong, in that case, for the government to exercise their rights in confiscating his property, as the government has higher might, and might is justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What had been discussed here are all based on theory. In the real world, it is not going to be as straight forward as what being portray here. However, while it is not morally correct to practice tax evasion, we should also strive towards a system that minimizes morally wrong practices, such as corruption, tyranny, etc. Essentially, the future of a country is what we wish for it as a collective, and we as an individual has the power to decide what a country should be like.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Discussing tax evasion with political philosophy</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-02/tax-escape.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[意見] 關於逃稅的那件事，是對還是錯？</title><link href="/blog/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC%E9%80%83%E7%A8%85/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[意見] 關於逃稅的那件事，是對還是錯？" /><published>2019-02-21T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC%E9%80%83%E7%A8%85</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC%E9%80%83%E7%A8%85/">&lt;p&gt;如果英文是你的首選，而且也選着讀英文，可是到&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/tax-escape/&quot;&gt;這裏&lt;/a&gt;讀取英文版本的這篇文章。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;前言&quot;&gt;前言&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;前幾天，在和朋友聚會的時候，我們討論關於我們各自未來的生涯規劃。我的這個朋友正在大學就讀會記科系。她說她正在拿着一個專業文憑的考試，而且這個考試很難。她就記述了關於她的大部分同學都有一些關於會記的工作經驗，這些經驗通常都是從假期的時候做兼職拿到的。這樣一說，我們可以知道她並沒有過類似的工作經驗。很自然的我也就問她爲什麼她不在假期的時候去找類似的兼職呢？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;聽了這個疑問之後，她就回答道那是因爲她想到畢業之後需要做同樣的工作，她就已經不想要現在做類似的工作了。與其在假期的時候尋找關於會記的兼職，她寧願尋找任何其他的兼職，好比如說：服務員，銷售員，等等。我想了一想，就讀會記科系其實不只是能夠成爲會記師，其實也可以在財務業，銀行業或其他有關聯的行業做工。所以，我便詢問道她有沒有想過財務業，銀行業或其她的行業。然後，她便回答道她並沒有對這幾個行業有興趣，而她比較有興趣的地方在稅務或商事法。這也是這個課題的由來。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;談到稅務，自然離不開逃稅了。當時，我們變談到關於大部分的人都想要逃稅，而如果進入關於稅務的行業，便很大機率將會是稅務顧問。當一個稅務顧問，就算是在一些正當的會計師事務所，好比如四大，也很有可能會牽涉到非法逃稅，只不過是在什麼的情況下發生。逃稅大概沒有對任何人造成傷害，而且這些繳的稅務也有可能會被勿用，那麼其實逃稅沒有什麼錯啊，我當時是這樣想的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;可是，真的是如此嗎？那天回到家睡覺前，我就想了想，最終得到了我個人的答案。這答案也是我今天會在這裏討論的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;稅務，定義爲政府強制向納稅人（個人或商業機構）征收貨幣或資源。那麼，我們應該要問的問題是政府有什麼權利徵收稅務？不過，在明白政府有什麼權利徵收稅務之前，我們要知道要明白政府的義務是什麼？而在那之前，我們要想想如果政府並不存在，會是一個什麼的樣子？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;自然狀態&quot;&gt;自然狀態&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;自然狀態，定義爲在一個沒有任何更高等權利純在的世界，可以爲明白爲沒有政府的世界。諾今天政府突然不見了，會是什麼樣子的？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在17世紀，有位著名的英國政治哲學家托马斯·霍布斯（Thomas Hobbes）認爲，在自然狀態，每一個人都會擁有所有的權利，這也包括偷盜，綁架，虐殺，等等。當每個人都有所有的權利的時候，對錯並不純在。一個人殺另一個人，殺害者並沒有錯，因爲他只是運用了他的權利而已，而被殺者也沒有對，因爲沒有任何的東西阻止他想盡辦法不被殺，或事先殺虐對方。這就是這位學者著名格言的由來。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;社會契約理論的奠基者、沒有了政府的自然狀態是「孤獨、貧困、污穢、野蠻和短暫的」 ― 托马斯·霍布斯&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;擁有如此極端的看法，自然也會有另一極端的看法。在18世紀，擁有另一位著名的政治哲學家讓-雅克·盧梭（Jean-Jacques Rousseau）想象一羣人出海旅遊，我們在其中。在海上乘船是，突然翻船了，而船上的人也被漂浮到一個無人島。在無人島上並不純在任何的更高權利純在，代表着自然狀態，我們會做出什麼舉動呢？試圖把這個問題問一問幾個人，我相信拿到的答案多數會是和其他船上的人合作，想想辦法先如何能夠在島上生存，然後再合作想想如果逃出這個島外。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;他再給出另一個例子。試圖想象兩個獵人在一個深林裏面打獵，各自獵人各自尋找各自的獵物：兔子。突然，這兩個獵人相遇了，而前方也有一隻大象，他們會合作狩獵這個大象，還是攻擊對方阻止對方在自己的地區打獵呢？我相信各位的答案將會是合作把這個大象成功狩獵下來。這個原因是因爲打獵並不是零和博弈，也不是負和博弈，而是正和博野。當兩個人合作是，得到的利益將會是比總合兩方各自行動得到的另一來的更多。因此，不同於托马斯·霍布斯，他總結了人在自然狀態下，人人都會幫助其他人，是人能夠在的最好的狀態。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;如今不同以往，我們擁有了居多不同的理論來解釋人類狀況，而這些狀況可以用來試圖建構自然狀態。其中之一包括查爾斯·達爾文（Charles Darwin）的自然選擇。如今，我們明白了人類最基本自然目的是生存。能夠解釋人類所有舉動其中之一的原因是爲了生存。那麼，既然如此一說，讓-雅克·盧梭錯了嗎？我個人覺得他對了一半。在自然狀態下，一個人在遇到其他人的時候，很大機率會和對方合作，因爲合作爲各自帶來更大的生存機率。可是，當這一羣人開始組織獵人部落的時候，兩個部落合作再也不會再提高生存機率。反而，在越多人的情況下，與其增加生存機率，人與人之間的關係將不會比少人的來得好，爭執也更容易發生，而且既然關係不比少人時來得好，解決爭執的動機也降低了，自然帶來較低的生存機率。這也是托马斯·霍布斯所想象的世界，只不過與其每一個人各自「孤獨、貧困、污穢、野蠻和短暫的」,而是部落與部落之間都是「孤獨、貧困、污穢、野蠻和短暫的」。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不但如此，一個部落和其他部落合作不但降低各自生存機率，反而攻擊其他部落，掠奪他人的資源反而增加生存機率。一個部落沒有如我們現今先進的技術，自然很容易陷入資源短缺的狀態。剝奪他人部落資源能夠增加一個部落的資源，也更容易達到了資源充足的狀態，這樣生存機率也跟着上升。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;另外，我們現今也明白了主要暴力的三大來源，其中是：爲了自衛而使用暴力，爲了避免對方使用暴力而事先使用暴力，和爲了榮耀。以上只考慮了前兩者原因，並沒有考慮到第三原因。除了生存，其他動機能夠解釋人類舉動的也包括：快樂，意義和權利。榮耀，在某些情況下解釋了能夠增加生存機率，生存卻不能完全解釋容易。反而，榮耀概括了其他三個人類舉動的動機：快樂，意義和權利。得到榮耀的快樂感，追求榮耀爲生存意義，最求榮耀得來的權利，這些都是在人類不需要擔心生存的時候更加在意的，即使這些動機會降低生存機率。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那麼，自然狀態自然是逃不掉暴力了。明白了這些，政府的義務到底是什麼？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;社會契約&quot;&gt;社會契約&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;自然狀態，暴力是否發生不重要，重要在暴力發生的可能性高不高。暴力不增加生存機率，而大部分個體都想要提高自身的生存機率遠離暴力，那麼這也就是社會契約的功能。自然狀態，每一個人都擁有所有的權利，而這些個體擁有的權力造就了我們不可取的結果，包括辛辛苦苦得來的資源被盜竊，伴侶被搶奪，家人被屠殺，等等。即使這些都是每個人不可取的結果，社會契約的功能也就是讓所有在這個契約生效的範圍內的個體給出他自身並不是很需要的權利，例如偷盜，搶劫，虐殺等等，以換取被從保護的利益。該社會契約生效的範圍也被成爲國家。所有居住在其國家內的個體也被稱爲公民。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那麼，問題是，到底什麼權利是在一個公民願意犧牲來換取其利益呢？這一個問題是歷史以來至今所有不同的政治哲學家探討的問題。這是一個很廣的問題，所以我們今天只會專注在一些理所當然絕大多數人類願意犧牲來得到的權利，這些都包括：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;犧牲使用暴力的權利來換取社會安寧&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;犧牲偷盜和搶奪的權利來換取財產權&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;犧牲強行性行爲的權利來換取被從未經雙方認可性行爲保護&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;犧牲殺虐的權利來換取性命保障&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;這些犧牲了的權利自然會被轉遇到維持社會契約的組織，也被稱爲政府。擁有了這些權利的政府在國家必須確保所有的公民遵從不侵犯所犧牲的權利，以及確保這些公民得到從其犧牲得到的利益。諾任何公民觸犯了其犧牲的權利，政府將應用被轉與至該政府的權利來對付其犯人，這包括：逮捕，監禁，拷問，鞭刑，以及死刑。那麼簡單來說，政府的工作將會是：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;保護社會次序與安寧&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;保障財產權&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;懲處使用了不應擁有該權利的個體&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;問題來了。我們所有的公民願意犧牲權利爲得到其中的利益，可是這些利益必須由政府來保障，而其保障並非免費，這也就到我們的下一個課題：稅務。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;稅務&quot;&gt;稅務&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;政府是一個組織，組織定義爲一羣個體集合組織成爲的。政府這個組織並非慈善機構，其組織內的個體也需換取利益來執行該任務。沒了這些利益，大部分個體將不會留在其組織內，以導致此政府無法執行該應執行的義務。那麼，其組織內的個體所求利益之一也包括貨幣或其他的資源。自然地，這些需要將轉遇到受益者身上，也就是該國家的公民。那麼，徵收稅務，該從這些公民徵收多少的稅務呢？我們已經討論過了這個這個政府的義務以及公民得到的利益，那麼得到比較多利益的公民自然也應該繳比較多的稅務。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;以上其中一個政府的義務是保障財產權。越多的財產自然需要越多的資源來保護，那麼收入越高或財產越高的公民自然也應該繳較多的稅務。這裏，我們可以把一個機構同樣看待爲一羣的公民，政府依然必須確保該機構的財產權，所以機構也該依照其機構的收入來繳稅。這也就是爲什麼如今的稅務率完全取決與收入的數量。越高的收入，需繳的稅務也就越高。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;明白了這些，我們應該探討，逃稅也就意味着什麼？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;逃稅&quot;&gt;逃稅&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;當我們購買物品，我們必須付該物品應有的價值。同樣的，想要確保自己的財產權自然需要繳付該保護財產權的代價。繳付應繳的價值以獲得該回報是天經地義。當一個人逃稅，這一就意味着一個人繳了少過他應該繳的價值。那麼，當一個人繳了少過他應繳的價值時，政府總收入減少。當絕多數人逃稅時，總收入也就降低很多，而當總收入降低到達了政府無法維持的範圍時，政府也不得增加稅務率以達到能夠維持政府機構運行的收入。這樣一來，逃稅也意味着把自己應該繳的費用轉移到了其他老實繳稅的人的身上。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;理論上雖然是這麼的一個情況，可是很多人會認爲繳付給政府的資源絕大部分都會被勿用，所以既然會被勿用，那繳稅也不就意味着幫助這些勿用稅務的人嗎？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;可是，會勿用稅務的人始終會勿用稅務。所以，不交稅的人依然會把自己應繳的費用放在了別人的身上，因爲勿用稅務的人不會理會總稅務收入而勿用其稅務。當只有小部分的人繳稅，這些稅收入將會被這些勿用稅務的人勿用，剩下的短缺也會以提高稅務的方式來獲得。當然，勿用稅務的人並沒有對過，因爲勿用稅務也同樣的意味着把自己享福的費用放在了別人的身上，所以雖然我們不應該逃稅，我們也應該積極地支持任何反貪污的政治或非政治運動。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;當然，我相信有人會認爲，把費用放在了別人的身上有什麼錯了？威力就是正義，不對嗎？就像在自然狀態下，有威力的人自然就是對的。從文明歷史以來，流傳下來的歷史都會是從擁有強大威力文明社會的角度而描述的，威力纔是正義。歷史書上記載的各文明社會榮耀繁榮，這些也不是把自己享福的費用放在了別人的身上。這樣一來，成功逃稅沒有錯，因爲逃稅來得不易，能夠成功逃稅也需要繳付該想要成功逃稅的費用，這個需繳的費用是社會權利象徵的其中一種。而付得起這個費用的人擁有把自己享福的費用轉遇到別人身上的權利，因爲他們擁有的是威力，而威力就是正義。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;依照以上邏輯，那麼停止繳交稅務也就是停止獲得政府供給的財產權，政府這時也將會有搶奪該逃稅人的財產，因爲威力是正義。所以，依照威力是權力的邏輯，逃稅依然不對，因爲在一個國家內，政府擁有最大的威力，因爲政府是所有人民轉移權利形成的，所以沒有任何一個個體會擁有比政府強大的威力，威力是正義，繳稅給政府以換得其利益自然也是正義。諾一個個體或組織擁有比該國家更大的威力時，該個體或組織將不會再有繳稅的義務，同時政府也沒有保護該組織的義務了。這時，威力才會是正義，因爲雙方不再被社會契約束縛，雙方都擁有所有的權利至另一方。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;總結&quot;&gt;總結&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;雖然威力是正義，可是在一個社會契約內，放棄了該權利的我們，威力再也不是正義。在一個社會契約內，犧牲權利來換取利益的我們雖然形成了比我們所有人更大權利的形體（政府），政府的威力也只不過是我們所有人民的總合。所以，身爲在一個社會契約內的個體，我們不應停止探討社會契約論。當政府勿用了被寄託的權力是，該國的個體也可以聚集會該犧牲的權利並且創造一個新的政府，這也被稱之爲抗議。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;當然，理論上，國家和國家之間唯一存在更高權利的組織將會是一羣國家聚集在一起創造出來的組織，比如聯合國。可是，如今依然擁有不在該組織下的國家。那麼，理論上，這些國家將會有所有的權力至其他的所有的國家，而聯合國該聯盟也有所有的權利至該不在旗下的國家。但如今，大部分的國家都明白了各國家合作給予各國家的利益，加上今日戰爭的費用已經遠高於能夠獲得的利益，大部分的國家再也沒有使用所有權利至其他國家的動機了，所以我對任何國家使用該權利保持樂觀，相信未來一日，所有的國家再也沒有使用該權利的動機，因爲使用該權利的費用遠超於至今的費用，而利益也遠低於至今能獲得的利於（雖然之間利益已經遠低於費用了）。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">探討從政治哲學的角度看逃稅，是對還是錯？</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-02/tax-escape.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Anime] Paprika: Subconscious</title><link href="/blog/paprika-subconscious/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Anime] Paprika: Subconscious" /><published>2019-01-20T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-01-20T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/paprika-subconscious</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/paprika-subconscious/">&lt;p&gt;Paprika is an anime released in 2006, co-written and directed by Satoshi Kon. It is a very good anime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had been reading quite a few that are related to psychoanalysis and dream interpretation. After that, I came across this anime, call Paprika, which I had been wanted to watch it for a long time, and finally decided to watch it right before this writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one main takeaway which I get from the movie, which is the whole reason why I write this blog in the first place. So, without further delay, let’s get started into the summary of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoiler Alert!!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This blog contains spoiler. If you had not watched the Anime, I strongly advise you to do so before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the near future, a device call “DC Mini” is invented, allowing people going into other people dreams. This device is soon stolen by someone in order to inject dream into other people. As the plot progress, it found that the person who stole the device is no other than the chairman of the research institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the device is incomplete, the device is faulty. Prolonged usage of the device will result in undesired consequences. Besides, no proper access control is being programmed into the device, which results in everyone can enter everyone else dream, and had been taken advantage by the dream terrorist (the chairman).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the plot progress, they try to save everyone who had been trapped inside the dream by overcoming all the obstacle. As they successfully done so, they arrive back into reality. However, when they are back to reality, they soon found that reality had merged with the dream. The creature of the dream are everywhere, and everyone started to dream and turning into various dream personas. It is chaos everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after that, the chairman had gone back to reality as a giant monster and attempt to destroy the world. Lastly, Atsuka and Paprika merge back into one being, sucking out the chairman dream, thus defeating the chairman and return to the world back to reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-main-takeaway&quot;&gt;My Main Takeaway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the final part of the movie, where the detective finally is able to overcome his repressed trauma, and shoot the terrorist, all the dream had ended. Everyone who trapped inside the dream went back to reality. However, something wrong happens. The reality had merged with the dream, and everyone, in reality, is dreaming while they are awake. All the dolls, festival, marching group, and many more, which originally only appear in the dream, appear out in the reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of it, chaos. People who are originally in the reality started to become a part of the dream, turn into some weird persona and merge into the march or doing whatever they do not dare to do in the reality, such as performing some violent activity or overthrow the people on top of the hierarchy. There are cars running into buildings everywhere, there is also robot eating up others human (Tokita’s persona as a giant robot, eat Atsuko after seeing her).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I started to think, a dream is our repressed conscious, and dream appears as a dream because our conscious had lower it’s guard when we are sleeping, hence came our repressed conscious. We repress our conscious every single day. When we read a piece of news about corruption happening in our government, we repressed the anger instead of expressing the anger toward people around us by punching them. When we are scolded by a teacher/lecturer/boss for doing something wrong, we, again, repress it instead of expressing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conscious that we had repress is not just limited to the scenarios that are as big as had been mentioned above, it can even be something as small as not being late to work/class where the emotion of not wanting to go early are being repressed, or not opening the angpao immediately after receiving one because culture restriction, where the desire or opening it are being repressed. Of course, in order for dream-formation, there need to be much more condition to fulfill, which will not be discussed here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we dream while awake, it simply means release all our repressed conscious to the reality and expressing it through any form of action. Perhaps, in order to maintain order, or letting a society works, each and everyone of us has to repress a certain part of our conscious. The thought of being able to dream while awake will result in nothing but chaos. Since each and every one of us has to repress some of our conscious, repressing too much will eventually meeting a backslash, which this is where the function of a dream comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Jung, the function of a dream is integrating conscious and unconscious, and he called it individuation. Take the detective, for example, his repressed conscious of making a movie are revealed to him in his dream, thus giving him a chance of achieving his dream and letting him become the individual he wanted to be. Therefore, the moment when the detective shot the terrorist, it is the moment when his conscious merging with his unconscious, successfully achieving his dream, it is also the end of the dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same applied to Freud’s theory of dream at the later stage of his career. Despite earlier in his career, his theory of the function of a dream is to grant wishes that the dream owner wishes subconsciously, he found that dream can act as a function of giving a chance of fulfilling a dream and overcome trauma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my main takeaway in the movie is dream contribute to us subconsciously much more than what most of us aware of, and we should never think about integrating dream into reality, as they are meant to complement each other and to think that is to result in nothing but chaos.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What happen when dream merge with reality?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-01/paprika.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Book] Book Rewind 2018 &amp;amp;#x1F44F &amp;amp;#x1F44F</title><link href="/blog/book-rewind-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Book] Book Rewind 2018 &amp;#x1F44F &amp;#x1F44F" /><published>2019-01-09T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-01-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/book-rewind-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/book-rewind-2018/">&lt;p&gt;It’s the first day of 2019 and happy new year! Our life expectancy, since the moment of this writing, had officially decreased by another year, again! So, let’s hope we have another great year coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the title implies, it’s a rewind of the books that I had read over the past year. Over the past year, I had read a number of books, and this blog will be a short review of these books that I had read during that period. Although it’s a book rewind for 2018, the first few books which I mention here might be books I read at the end of 2017 but I had forgotten when do I read them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1---utopia-merlin-coverley&quot;&gt;#1 - Utopia, Merlin Coverley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-utopia.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Utopia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first book in this list is Utopia, written by Merlin Coverley. This is a book where I bought the end of 2017 in Big Bad Wolf at The Mines. At that time, I am very interested in anything related to philosophy. I went to Big Bad Wolf, thinking to buy a few books which are related to philosophy and start the journey of philosophy. So, this is one of the books I bought, together with The Great Philosophers by Stephen Laws, The Year 1000 by Robert Lacey, Apocalypse by John Michael Greer and The Path by Michael Puett.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I didn’t manage to finish Apocalypse due to unfamiliarity with history. However, I finish The Great Philosophers before reading this book. It is an introductory book to philosophy, cover numerous famous philosophers and a summary of their idea. Since I read this book in 2017, it will not be discussed here. The Year 1000 and The Path, on the other hand, will be discussed in the later part of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, wandering in Big Bad Wolf, I came across this book, name Utopia. “Utopia, the perfect world, interesting topic, what does the writer has to say about it”, so I thought and I bought that book. Utopia is a book that discusses numerous different utopian ideas. As I am yet a frequent reader at that time, it is not an easy read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, it discusses numbers of utopian idea introduce by past people, often philosophers and writers. As the book discusses these ideas in a chronological order of which the idea had been introduced by the original person who came up with the idea, we can see how these ideas evolve, becoming more and more sophisticated over time. This is mainly due to people improving their idea on top of the insights provided by the people in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a common characteristic of these utopian societies, which is while it might sound like a utopian to the people it the past, it sounds rather dystopian today. By changing perspective, an utopian may turn into a dystopian. These ideas are utopian ideas during that period are potentially due to the social status, cultures and living condition of that period. By looking at the utopian idea of the period, it reflects the culture of that period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the existence of good creates the existence of evil. Good and evil is nothing but the different side of the same coin. In a world where good does not exist, evil too will cease to exists, due to the relatives of evil to the good no longer exists. Perhaps, these ideas are accepted as an utopian society in the past, means nothing but the living condition of that period are simply far worse than the utopian society itself. Looking back at it, we have nothing but to be grateful that we are born in this period. Probably, people in the future, looking back to the current ideal society, feels the same as how we look at the past utopian ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2---the-year-1000-robert-lacey&quot;&gt;#2 - The Year 1000, Robert Lacey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-year-1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Year 1000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second book, The Year 1000 by Robert Lacey. The Year 1000 is a book that talks about how does life in the year 1000 look like. As mention above, I bought this book during Big Bad Wolf. I already forget why do I buy this book during that time. It is probably because “Wow the first millennium, how can a cave life even elaborate into a whole book?” or “Wow how does life in the first millennium looks like back then when they do not have any technology?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can guess from what I had said, the first millennium is probably much more technological advance than I think of them before I read the book. Certainly, I forget some of the Chinese Civilization, Ancient Greek Civilization, and another Civilization comes before the first millennium, where they no longer live in a cave or to live a life of stone age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is made up of 12 chapters, and you guess it, each chapter represents how life looks like at each month of the year. Certainly, it is a very different period to live in comparison to ours. One of the examples would be the month before the harvest season. In the book, the author calls the months “the hunger gap”, where it is the month where there is a shortage of food, and the gap between the poor and the rich are more obvious than never before. Besides, there is also a festival celebrating the harvest season, where there is an abundance of food. Unlike today, where we have an abundance of food 365 days per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3---the-path-michael-puett--christine-gross-loh&quot;&gt;#3 - The Path, Michael Puett &amp;amp; Christine Gross-Loh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-the-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Path&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third book, The Path, yet another book I bought in Big Bad Wolf. The Path is a book about Ancient Chinese Philosophy. The reason why I buy this book is that it is one of the little books that I can find in Big Bad Wolf about philosophy, and I also have some interest in Chinese philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Chinese myself, it feels weird to read a book about Ancient Chinese Philosopher from a western writer. Certainly, the writer of the book is a professor of Chinese History at Harvard University. Without a doubt, he certainly knows more about Chinese culture, history, and philosophy than me. It is a very good book, and it did change some of the perspectives on how I look at things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about Ancient Philosophy, what comes to a lot of people mind is outdated, non-practical, irrelevant, dogma, etc. While the impression of non-practical, dogma and irrelevant may mainly come from branches like metaphysics or related branches, irrelevant and outdated might still be a concern for a modern reader. However, the writer does aware of these factors, and the book mainly concerns itself about the practical aspect of Ancient Chinese philosophies that are still relevant to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these philosophies came from more than a millennium, there are still a lot where we can learn from them. Back then, their science, logic, mathematics, physics, psychology, etc, might not be as developed as we do today, however, they still need to deal with human relationship, life, hardship, etc, just like us. By learning as-if ritual by Confucious, it might give us a different perspective on looking at a relationship. By learning Mencius philosophy, we learn a different perspective on looking at making choices. By learning inward training, we learn yet another perspective on looking at the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from the conventional impression on ancient philosophies, these philosophies not only far from irrelevant, but they are also relevant to us that it can give us extra perspectives. The more perspective we get to look at things, the more objective we can on making the right decision, instead of just blindly reacting to our emotion. This will without a doubt a book that I will recommend to people, especially if they are new to philosophy and not a frequent reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4---beyond-good--evil-friedrich-nietzsche&quot;&gt;#4 - Beyond Good &amp;amp; Evil, Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-beyond-good-and-evil.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beyond Good &amp;amp; Evil&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next book, Beyond Good &amp;amp; Evil by Friedrich Nietzsche. This is a philosophy book about ideas that Nietzsche expands on his previous work, Thus Spoke Zarathustra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As naive as I could, I thought I would be able to understand the book at that time, bought the book, and start reading it. It is still one of the most difficult books to read up until today, along with Thus Spoke Zarathustra, yet another book of him. Before reading this book, I had finished a few other philosophy books, full of myself, believing that I can do the same for this book, grasp everything idea inside, not knowing what actually is waiting for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, reading the book, I am able to understand why so many people misunderstood him. Those are mainly due to taking his word out of context. It is also very interesting to read some of the ideas about Übermensch before reading a book specifically about the said concept. But, as difficult as the book is, there are some of the chapters that I believe I will never be able to understand it, mainly due to the requirement of understanding the German culture itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that even now I am still not prepared to read the book. I will come back to this book again in the future when I think I am more prepared, and hopefully able to understand more than the first read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5---nineteen-eighty-four-george-orwell&quot;&gt;#5 - Nineteen Eighty-Four, George Orwell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-1984.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1984&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next book, 1984. 1984 is the first fiction appear in the list. 1984 is a dystopian totalitarian fiction written by George Orwell, which I had already done 2 blogs about it, namely &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/book-1984-social-construct/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/book-1984-thought-and-mind/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up till today, it is still one of my favorite books. The journey of reading the book is surely one of the most interesting journeys you can have. It is not just the plot that is interesting, the ideas that discuss inside are also interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole book is a vision of the dark future the author have if the world continues pushing the communism narratives. This cannot be blamed because the author lives in the world where there are Soviet Union, Hitler, Communist Party of China and Communism of North Korea. Lucky as we are, the world learns from history, knowing what can go wrong, and many people putting efforts into avoiding such things happen again every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another book which a lot of people always contrast it against this book, which is Brave New World by Aldous Huxley. It is another dystopian totalitarian novel, but having a complete, almost opposite concepts of what 1984 have. It’s been difficult to get on hand one of them, but I wish I can get on hand one of them as soon as possible, read it and make a comparison between both of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6---the-prince-machiavelli&quot;&gt;#6 - The Prince, Machiavelli&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-the-prince.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Prince&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sixth book, The Prince by Machiavelli. The prince is a book about politics that written specifically for new prince of the time on how they should manage a country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machiavellianism is a word used to describe someone with dark personalities, duplicitous interpersonal style, lack of morality and lack of empathy. The reason for the word having such meaning is mainly due to this book, The Prince.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the prince, it teaches the political theory that takes any means necessary to keep one in power. It talks about how morality differs from one person to another, and the prince naturally should have a different set of morality from normal people. To see why people hate those theories, one of the theory advice the prince to command his subordinate to exercise violence during a politically unstable period and betray the subordinate at the time when politics had come stable, making him a leader which people like by sacrificing the subordinate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are certainly not acceptable by the moral standard of the majority of the people. However, we need to understand where Machiavelli came from. He lives in a period of extreme political instability, and people at that time wish for nothing but political stability. This is why he wrote this book. In fact, he also wrote other books about the republic where he favors more than a monarch. The book, in my opinion, is merely a product of instability of the time, and he will also not agree with it during a stable political period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7---a-guide-to-the-good-life-william-birvine&quot;&gt;#7 - A Guide To The Good Life, William B.Irvine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-guide-to-good-life-stoicism.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stoicism&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next book is A Guide To The Good Life by William B.Irvine. This is a book about Stoicism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stoicism is a life philosophy. Life philosophy is important because it guides you to live the most out of your life, just like a compass guide you to your destination in a journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of stoicism is dated back to ancient Greek. Just like ancient Chinese philosophy, there might be some of the things that are outdated, but this book is the version that focuses on parts which are relevant to us. Not only that, but this book also spend a lot of time addressing common criticism towards Stoicism. Such an example would be demonstrated below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the common practice in stoicism is to always expect the negative outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;When you wake up in the morning, tell yourself: the people I deal with today will be meddling, ungrateful, arrogant, dishonest, jealous and surly. They are like this because they can't tell good from evil. But I have seen the beauty of good, and the ugliness of evil, and have recognized that the wrongdoer has a nature related to my own - not of the same blood and birth, but the same mind, and possessing a share of the divine. And so none of them can hurt me. No one can implicate me in ugliness. Nor can I feel angry at my relative, or hate him. We were born to work together like feet, hands and eyes, like the two rows of teeth, upper and lower. To obstruct each other is unnatural. To feel anger at someone, to turn your back on him: these are unnatural.&quot; ― Marcus Aurelius, Meditations &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These practice advice to always expect the negative outcome, such as you will lose your job, your girlfriend will leave you, etc. By having this negative outcome, if it did happen, you will not feel as sad as you would have expected the outcome otherwise. However, if the outcome is otherwise, it would simply be a bonus, and you will feel happy about it. This practice is commonly being criticized by others with the argument goes: if you do not shed a tear when you look at your child past away, you would not have the happiness seeing your first born child smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, it addresses the argument by expecting the negative outcome, for instance thinking your child is going to past away, you will treasure the current time with your child more than if you had not expected such. This book not only addresses common criticism people gave to stoicism, but it also improves on top of the existing stoicism method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one of the example from the book, which one will require to take a lot of reading from a lot of different books about stoicism to come to such an understanding. This is because there is hardly one book that covers most part of stoicism, as complete as this book, and yet, at the very same time, the modern version of it. Hence, the writer decides to compose a single book that covers most essence of stoicism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book, in my opinion, this is a book where everyone needs to read. However, it does not mean that everyone should practice Stoicism after reading it. There is a lot of philosophy of life, ranging from Epicureanism, Hedonism, Cynicism, etc. However, after reading this book, to practice Stoicism or not is totally up to the reader, as he is the one who lives his life, and it would benefit one to know the existence of Stoicism, if not the philosophy of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8---leviathan-thomas-hobbes&quot;&gt;#8 - Leviathan, Thomas Hobbes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-leviathan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leviathan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet another philosophy book, Leviathan, by political philosopher Thomas Hobbes. This book is about political philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about political philosophy, the name that comes to our mind would be Hobbes, Rousseau, and Locke. All 3 of them comes up with a very different political philosophy theory. To discuss the reason behind why they arrive at different theory, we need to understand what is political philosophy in the very first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Political philosophy discusses about the role of government. When we discuss the role of government, we first need to think of what does it looks like if the government does not exists. When we know what does it looks like when a government does not exist, and we understand what we want our government to be like, then we can only discuss about what is the roles of government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as you guess, all 3 political philosophers mentioned had a very different view on the state of nature, which is a state where any form of greater power than an individual does not exist. In Hobbes view, in the state of nature, human will kill each other in order to survive. In Rousseau however, humans are good and will help each other by nature in order to survive. On the other hand, John Locke thinks that humans are born with certain human right. All of these leads to very different opinion on political philosophy theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people today will criticize them for their wrong theory, however, eventually, they are living in the pre-Darwinism period. Now, we know, in the state of nature, we might help each other or kill each other, totally depending on the situation for the sake of survival, but they do not have such inspiration to build their idea on top of it. So, these theories might be no longer relevant, however, understanding their reasoning might help in understanding political philosophy in today’s context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9---in-the-orchard-the-swallows-peter-hobbs&quot;&gt;#9 - In The Orchard, The Swallows, Peter Hobbs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-in-the-orchard-the-swallows.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In the orchard, the swallows&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second fiction in the list, In The Orchard, The Swallows by Peter Hobbs. The book talks about a story of a young man who gets into tragic after some romance relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, the story goes by a young man who falls in love with a woman. For the woman came from a family of a different social class with the protagonist, he gets into some argument with the woman’s father, and eventually sent to jail without explanation from the authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the book, we can see how social class and separate human being into a superior and inferior group is inhuman. But, what most important of all, is meaning. In the number of years where the protagonist able withstands to live within the jail, all of these are due to the belief where he can see the woman when he leaves the jail. It is the meaning, that helps him withstand the years in the jail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;He who has a why to live for can bear almost any how.&quot; ― Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This point is being shown in the novel. A lot of part of the novel narrates how the protagonist withstands all the sufferings that he has within the jail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10---understanding-objectivism-leonard-peikoff&quot;&gt;#10 - Understanding Objectivism, Leonard Peikoff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-understanding-objectivism.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Understanding Objectivism&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, yet another philosophy book, Understanding Objectivism by Leonard Peikoff. This is a book, not written by Leonard Peikoff, but a text version of Leonard Peikoff lecture class on Objectivism. The book composes of the whole semester of Leonard Peikoff’s Objectivism lecture with minor changes on the way of organizing and grouping things to suit for reading. Such minor changes are simple things like grouping the question asked in the lecture class to the end of the chapter, or something similar, hence preserving the presence of Leonard Peikoff in the lecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several very useful things discussed in the book that can greatly improve our lives, which include epistemology, subjective versus objective and the use of logic and emotion. By understanding epistemology, it helps us better in understanding and learning things or even reasoning. A lot of people, not understanding subjective and objective, while making an argument without understanding both is a waste of time. Objectivity should be looking at things in a way that putting as little our own perspective as possible, looking at one thing as it is. Meanwhile, subjective is looking at things from a particular perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to reach subjectivity, it requires to pass through the argument of objectivity. For example, randomly go on a street killing people in a civilization context is objectively wrong because Social Contract exists, protecting us from randomly getting killed by giving up our own right of killing other people. To randomly go on a street killing people is to go against own life because doing so would simply causing one to either get killed by other people in self-defense on the street or death sentences. So, when not passing objectivity, there is no need to discuss subjectivity or one preference of going on a street randomly killing people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, choosing a career between an artist and programmer is subjective, because both options are not objectively wrong, and both at the very same time objectively right for one who made the career choice as a career allow one to preserve his own life by earning wages and pay for necessity. However, once it reaches the realm of subjectivity, there is again, no need of argument, because it is simply up to the perspective or one preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book also discusses about the use of both emotion and logic. One main reason pushing people away from practicing philosophy is they think that practicing philosophy means to use only logic, not emotion. However, there are different usage in both emotion and logic. Emotion act as a tool for us to hold a lot of information, while logic act as a tool of cognitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate it, say, when we went to listen to a speech, the speaker will give out a lot of points. Here, emotion act as a tool for us to remember a lot of crucial information, such as we get angry when the speaker giving out a certain point, which all the point gave out by the speaker is able to compress into the emotion: anger. Post-speech, logic comes into play to evaluate the speech, where we evaluate our emotion, examining whether why do we have such emotional reaction and should the points given by speaker correct or wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, I think this is a very useful and practical book. There are of course a lot another point that being discussed in the book, and above is merely a few of the very useful point being discussed. I believe this book able to allow more people to be more objective about things, and I would surely recommend everyone to read this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;11---thus-spoke-zarathustra-friedrich-nietzsche&quot;&gt;#11 - Thus Spoke Zarathustra, Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-thus-spoke-zarathustra.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Thus Spoke Zarathustra&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next book, the third fiction in the list, Thus Spoke Zarathustra by Friedrich Nietzsche. Forgetting the lesson learned from the first book of Nietzsche, I think, “maybe fiction is easier to read”, hence I started reading the book. Learning lesson is part of our life, but forgetting the lesson we learn, maybe, is also a major part of our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this book follows a man, Zarathustra, goes on a journey of creating an Übermensch. He stays deep inside the mountain, acquires a bunch of wisdom, going down to the town, trying to preach his idea, and eventually meet a backslash from the people. He then moves on to the journey of finding people who suit to be Übermensch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book, fiction, is slightly easier to read than Beyond Good and Evil, but the reason why I can understand better for this book is that while I reading the book, every time finishing a chapter, I will read the interpretation of the chapter online, and cross-reference with my own interpretation. Here, finally, I realize, why his book is so difficult to read. When he uses the word “the wise”, it does not signify someone who is wise, rather someone who deem wise by the majority of people. When he uses the word “virtue”, he does not meant it as “virtue” as the word represent, but the virtue being adopted by the masses. The way he uses the word makes it difficult to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, it is also not the easiest book to read. The book is not well structured. He wrote the book in a very short period of time, and only further expand the idea in the books Beyond Good &amp;amp; Evil and Genealogy of Moral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a book for everyone, but also a book for no one. He knows that this is a book where everyone needs to read, but also knows that when people read his books, the majority of people will not be able to fully understand him intellectually, or misunderstood him. Although I am the former, I still think this is a very good book to read, and reading this book allow us to put down a lot of burdens that being placed on us since born, and also encourage one to strive towards the best version of oneself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;12---before-the-fact-francis-iles&quot;&gt;#12 - Before The Fact, Francis Iles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-before-the-fact.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Before The Fact&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more fiction now, Before The Fact by Francis Iles. This is a novel with the story goes by a woman who married to a murderer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the story, a woman, if I remember correctly, in the late twenties or early thirties, somewhat desperate for a partner, and eventually meet a man who seems to love her very much. They get married very soon after that. As the story progress, the women slowly found out that there is a lot of secrets that the man hiding from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title goes “before the fact”, indicating that this women, due to how desperate she is, despite the fact that a lot of proof point against his husband, she still tries to believe the otherwise, and eventually found out that his husband is a murderer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, this is a tales of how emotional can a human being be, and what are the consequences one might need to face when using emotion for the wrong things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;13---eureka-chad-orzel&quot;&gt;#13 - Eureka!, Chad Orzel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-eureka.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eureka&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 13th book is Eureka!, the first book in the list that is related to science. Eureka! is a book about scientific thinking and aim to discover the inner scientist of the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, the scientific method is described to the following few steps, include observe, hypothesize, testing and sharing. Every scientific discovery started with observing the phenomena. Once a phenomenon had been observed, the next step is to think and hypothesize why the phenomenon happens so. After that, it will be testing out the hypothesis if it is correct. A lot of people thinks the process stops after proving the hypothesis to be correct, but it doesn’t stop here, and the final step of the process is to share the result, hence making scientific advancement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main point of the book is not about the scientific method itself, but how often in our life we use the scientific method. Example, the first step of the scientific method is to observe, and naturally, observe involve collecting data. Biologist effort of collecting numbers of different species hoping to complete collecting every species is exactly the same with stamp collector trying to collect a full collection of stamps or we trying to collect achievement in games. The same goes to hypothesize, testing and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we end, quote Orzel Chad, “Like breathing, we are engaging in the scientific process much of the time, even if we don’t know it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;14---animal-farm-george-orwell&quot;&gt;#14 - Animal Farm, George Orwell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-animal-farm.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Animal Farm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As George Orwell’s 1984 fascinates me a lot, it makes me wanted to read him more. After that, I came across another of his book, Animal Farm, and I think to myself, “this sounds interesting”, so I bought it and started reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different from 1984, this novel seems like a version of 1984 that had been simplified by a lot. While 1984 has a very complete world setting, with a government, different social classes, etc, animal farm simply happens in an animal farm with different animals living in it. If the main idea behind 1984 is to tell people how scary it would be to live in a world of totalitarian state, Animal Farm will be a book to describe how a state can turn into a totalitarian state like one in 1984.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book started with animal trying to take over the farm from being colonized by the human, upon success, the leader of the protest become the leader of the animal farm. As the story progress, the leader of the animal farm slowly changing more and more rules to their own benefit, and eventually reach a state where it is no longer better than when human colonize the farm, instead even worse than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as the animal in the farm ages, and slowly dying, replacing with the next generation, it reaches a point where there’s no longer anyone who remember the life when human colonize the animal farm, and eventually it ends with the leader of the farm show their true face and sided with the human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not a happy story, but it shows us in the real world, how a politician can manipulate people into their own benefit, and slowly taking over the country, warning us to be more cautious of such situation, thus avoiding from living in such scary state in the very first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;15---the-rational-optimist-matt-ridley&quot;&gt;#15 - The Rational Optimist, Matt Ridley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-rational-optimist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rational Optimist&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I previously read a lot of pessimistic books, I wonder to myself, maybe I should read a few optimistic books. Looking into the list of book I have, I saw this book, The Rational Optimist by Matt Ridley, which I had bought it for some time and haven’t read it, so I decided to start reading this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the title suggests, the author of the book is not naturally optimist nor pessimist, he is simply being an optimist after looking at the facts, numbers, data, figures, etc, on the subject where most people pessimist about. All of this, include global warming, population growth, food shortage, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main point of the book is not global warming does not exist, not population growth is not an issue, neither food shortage never happen, but the trend of these issues are not as pessimistic as what the media portray them to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take population growth, for example, population growth used to be a problem many years ago, perhaps late 20th century, but many countries in the world showing them otherwise. However, although we say a lot of countries no longer has population growth, most population growth came from Africa, and they still have population growth up until today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this is also a point where the author aware of, and we should not ignore the fact that most of these country’s population are increasing at a decreasing rate, and as more and more of these places equip with more advanced medical facilities, they will eventually reach very low or negative population growth rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are also things that we should be pessimistic about, such as matter concern with a nuclear weapon. Current Nuclear technology is so advance that the nuclear bomb today is far stronger than both of the nuclear bomb that dropped during world war 2 combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main point of the book is eventually about we shouldn’t be as pessimistic as most people is on the matter where a lot of people pessimistic about. Things such as population growth, food shortage, global warming, and many more, is a real problem, and we should not just leave it alone, treating it as if it is not a problem, but neither should we be very pessimistic about it as what most media portraying them to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;16---antifragile-nassim-nicholas-taleb&quot;&gt;#16 - Antifragile, Nassim Nicholas Taleb&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-antifragile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Antifragile&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next book is Antifragile by Nassim Nicholas Taleb. This is a book about the whole concept of antifragile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this book, it talks about antifragile and contrast antifragile with fragile and robust. When we think of fragile, we think of something that breaks easily. So, if the word antifragile is completely opposite to fragile, what is antifragile? Most people will say: “doesn’t break easily”. It is actually not, but antifragile is something that can benefit from trying to break it, while something that doesn’t break easily is robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the author gives a lot of examples of fragile, robust and antifragile. What most of the time we think as robust of even antifragile is actually something completely opposite to it. First, he demonstrates with a self-employed with an employee. In a lot of people perception, self-employed have a much higher risk than being employed, where while self-employed has a very unstable income, an employed has stable income every single month. However, when we look at most self-employed, they do have unstable income, but at a longer time frame, the average income for said period is slightly less stable, if not equally stable with those that are employed, but once in an unfavorable condition, an employed can loss all the income meanwhile self-employed will still have a certain amount of income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it is here that makes a difference, where if an employed loses his job, say, at the late 40s, he will have a hard time recover from it, but not the same for self-employed. The self-employed, at a hard time, will be forced to improve himself to compete in order to survive, thus becoming the better version of himself, and on top of recovering back to the original position before the difficult period, he would have strived even further than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, employed are fragile, while one will have stable income if the economy remains stable, he will be hurt deeply and will be difficult to recover once hurt, where the antifragile, in this case, the self-employed, has a very high potential of gaining from the bad time as long as he is not hurt to the extent where he does not have any chance of recovering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the same concept can be applied to a lot of things, not just from those that mention in the book, but far beyond on that. It is a very good book, at least to the first half of the book, but the second half of the book becomes a book where there is a lot of self-contradictory statement, hence if one would like to read this book, I would advise to read it more critical than reading any other books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;17---world-order-henry-kissinger&quot;&gt;#17 - World Order, Henry Kissinger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-world-order.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;World Order&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we reach the last few books. Here we have World Order by Henry Kissinger. This is a book about the subject of world order. The book explains different world order in historical context and the evolution of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the book started with Westphalian Peace during 17th century Europe. He explains how the system is in place for keeping the world order. After that, it moves on to explain central imperium philosophy of China, then the theory of world order from an Islamic state, and lastly move on to the democratic idealism of the United State.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I mention quite a few of them above, the proportion that used to cover each is surely not the same, and a big part of the book is used to cover the democratic idealism of the United State. This makes me think nothing but this is a book that written to push the narratives of world order from the United State perspective to the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite that, as I did mention where I am not very well versed in history, this book does help me to equip with some historical knowledge, which is unexpected out of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;18---the-women-in-the-dunes-kobo-abe&quot;&gt;#18 - The Women In The Dunes, Kobo Abe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-women-in-the-dunes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Women in the Dunes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At almost the end of the year, I started reading this book, The Women in the Dunes, and finish it within 2 days. If you aware of the blogs that I have, I had already written a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/book-suna-no-onna-absurdism/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; for this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the fiction books that I had read which make me realize the if I only read non-fiction, I will be missing out a lot. Although saying such, there is, of course, a lot of fiction that is written solely for the purpose of entertainment without any depth towards it. Other fictions which make me think so is 1984 and animal farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is a lot of theme in the book aside from absurdism, such as spiritual rape, sexual desire, etc. All I cover in my blog is just one of the theme in the book, which is absurdism. It is a short but interesting read, and I believe that you might get different things out of the book from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;19---no-longer-human-osamu-dazai&quot;&gt;#19 - No Longer Human, Osamu Dazai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-no-longer-human.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;No Longer Human&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finish The women in the dunes in 2 days, what else I finish in 2 days? It’s No Longer Human by Osamu Dazai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another interesting book to read, written by an author who had attempted suicide several times before writing this book, and finally successfully suicide after finishing this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are aware of it, I had also written a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/book-no-longer-human-review/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; for this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading this book, you will sort of understands how the author thinks, and perhaps why he does what he does. A lot of things about him are hidden from everyone else, like putting a facade and living on for the rest of his life. Of course, as another entity, we will never know how they think at that moment, and it is only through their own writing, we get to know potentially how he think at a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is a fictionize autobiography of the author, and not everything inside is exactly what the author had experience, but through the writing, we at least know that to the very least, it’s something happen to him or people around him. It is a very interesting book to read, and I would surely recommend it if someone asking recommendation for fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;20---mans-search-for-meaning-victor-efrankl&quot;&gt;#20 - Man’s Search For Meaning, Victor E.Frankl&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-man-search-for-meaning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Man Search For Meaning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second last book, Man’s Search For Meaning by Victor E.Frankl. This is a book about introductory to his logotherapy which we will be discussed slightly later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author of this book is one of the survival in concentration camps during the Hitler period. In the book, he describes his experience in the concentration camp and what he sees within. He sees a lot of people who lost their meaning of life and eventually run into the fence (suicide by running into the high voltage fence). He also describes a lot of people who suddenly lost their meaning of life, and no longer want to live and just await the arrival of death. On the contrast, he also sees a lot of people with the strong will of survival. One of the common characteristics he sees within those is having a meaning of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life inside is extremely horrible. One only get a new pair of shoe every 6 months, regardless if the old shoe is still able to wear. If the shoe had been broken, even during winter, they have to went to work barefoot, working as hard labor. Also, they only get 2 meal per day, a piece of bread in the morning while a bowl of soup in the evening. With this amount of calories intake, they will without a doubt run into calories deficit, especially when their nature of work burns an extra amount of calories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagining a life inside a concentration camp, any reader, including me, without a doubt, has very high possibility having the thought that if we would be in their position we would have suicide long ago. The reason they had yet suicide is simply the meaning of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;He who has a why to live for can bear almost any how.&quot; ― Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logotherapy is essentially a method surround meaning. “Logo” in Greek is meaning, and logotherapy is a method where meaning is the center of the therapy. One of the perspective the book offer us is not to see what life has to offer to us, we have to see what we can offer to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of concentration camp, when we are hit by such hardship, we shouldn’t think of life no longer has anything to offer to us, but what we have to offer to life, which is a sacred opportunity that life provides to us to prove to it that we are able to overcome such hardship and become someone better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading this book, it is also where I realize such had been used in another book within this list: In The Orchard, The Swallows. In the book, the protagonist, constantly thinking about the one he loves, and eventually able to survive the time in the prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we keep saying meaning, it is not the kind of grand meaning of life, but rather the meaning to every event. For instance, the meaning of suffering in the gym is because one wants to become strong. Grand meaning of life is indeed difficult to even find one, but having all these meaning for all different event is so that in return hoping that one can find one meaning by almost the end of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;21---the-hero-with-a-thousand-faces-joseph-campbell&quot;&gt;#21 - The Hero With A Thousand Faces, Joseph Campbell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2019-01/book-the-hero-with-a-thousand-face.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Hero With A Thousand Faces&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we reach the last book of the list, which is The Hero With A Thousand Faces. This is a book that discusses about the general journey of hero in a lot of myths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, the journey of the myth can separate into 3 parts, which is departure, initiation and return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the journey, the hero will go on to an adventure. This can cause by many different factors, such as being cast away by his people or searching for power to defeat the more powerful villain. For example, in the recent Aquaman, the protagonist went on a journey to search for the legendary weapon. In Iron Man, being blast away, he went on to work on his Iron Man suit. In Bleach, during the Aizen Sousuke ark, the protagonist went on to learn the final Getsuga Tenshou. Buddha, after finding out life is suffering, he went on to an adventure in order to search for the truth. And the list continues…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, it will be the initiation. In the initiation stage, the hero will face several challenges that test him to see if he is capable of being a hero. Example, Aquaman, when searching for the legendary weapon, he faces the challenges of activating the secret message, decodes the message in the bottle, defeat the small villain, breaking through the trench, and lastly, face the legendary monster who guard the weapon. In Iron Man, it will be the technical challenges he faces making the suit. In Bleach, it will be the battle against the Hollow Zangetsu within him. For Buddha, it will be the difficulties he faces meditating trying to find the truth, and also the devil that came to disturb him from becoming a Buddha. And of course, the list continues…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final stage is the return. This is the stage upon when the hero attains the power, he returns back to the people and performs his hero duty. For example, in Aquaman, it will be uniting both the land and sea and avoid war coming from the sea. For Iron Man, it is defeating the villain. For Bleach, it is defeating Aizen Sousuke, who no one in the world can defeat him. For Buddha, it is not to defeat anyone, but to teach the people the wisdom that had gifted upon him. Of course, the list again goes on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, there is a lot more detailed analysis of myths, which impossible to put into this summary. This summary merely covers the surface of the book. In all the detailed analysis, it uses a lot of psychoanalysis jargon, which makes it a difficult read for people who are not well versed with psychoanalysis. However, this is also a book where it gives me extra fun watching Aquaman, which I would enjoy less originally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;end&quot;&gt;End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the end of the blog. In last year, I had read 21 books, which I am quite satisfied with. This year, hopefully, I can finish 36 books by the end of this year. Also, as you might aware, I had been reading a lot of non-fiction past year. In this year, I also want to read more fiction and some science-related book, especially quantum physics.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Yaaaah! It's rewind time! That's hot, that's hot!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2019-01/books.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Anime] Cowboy Bebop: Hedgehog</title><link href="/blog/cowboy-bebop-hedgehog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Anime] Cowboy Bebop: Hedgehog" /><published>2018-12-19T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-12-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/cowboy-bebop-hedgehog</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/cowboy-bebop-hedgehog/">&lt;p&gt;Cowboy Bebop is a masterpiece classic anime that released in 1998. It had become one of my favorite anime after watching it. Generally, when comparing episodic anime to serial anime, I would prefer a serial anime except for genre like comedy. However, there are 2 anime which is surely suited more like an episodic anime than a serial anime. They are キノの旅 (Kino no Tabi) and Cowboy Bebop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes this 2 anime so great as an episodic anime is the feeling of having the journey together with the protagonist of the anime. In Kino no Tabi, the protagonist, Kino, is a traveler who travels around the world and has a rule of staying only 3 days in every town he visited. So, every episode is like an experience in a new town together with the protagonist. It feels as if you visit a new town, see new things about the town, experience their culture, food, etc. It’s almost like the feeling of you actually traveling to a place where you never travel before, except the anime can have much more interesting concepts that can never happen in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same goes to Cowboy Bebop. Cowboy Bebop is an anime about space bounty hunter traveling around to hunt for bounty. Life of a bounty hunter is very much like a freelancer, where they get a new job from time to time, and they never have a fixed job or fixed income. So, most of the project is short, and every project is like a journey, and it is a repetition of starting a new project, doing it, and finishing the project. The same goes to a bounty hunter, where new bounty being announced to the public, then comes the journey of trying to hunt the target down, and finally either a success or failure. What different from this anime to Kino no Tabi is when Kino no Tabi is an anime where protagonist visiting a new town every episode, and rarely side character appears more than 1 episode, Cowboy Bebop get the character development of all 4 main characters (one of them is a dog).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the anime’s episode goes from one after another, more and more character development happens. Slowly from one episode to another, we learn more about each of the character, their hobby, personality, characteristics, and even their past. From one episode to another, we also learn about the development of the relationship between one character and another. As the anime advances, more and more events take place, and new concepts being introduced to the anime, and these will be discussed in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog contains spoilers, but these spoilers generally will not spoil your watching experience of the anime if you decide to watch it in the future as the anime is episodic anime, so continue as you wish to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hedgehog-dilemma&quot;&gt;Hedgehog Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hedgehog dilemma is a concept where I first came across when watching Neon Genesis Evangelion. When watching the anime, I had not fully understood it. At the time, I understand Hedgehog Dilemma at the definition level, but could not able to relate and have a conceptual understanding of Hedgehog Dilemma. Thanks to this anime, a few other books, interaction with peoples, etc, I finally able to has a deeper understanding of Hedgehog Dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-12/hedgehog.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hedgehog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about hedgehog dilemma, we need to know what is a hedgehog. Hedgehog is an animal with a lot of spikes at their back. These spike act as a defense mechanism for them when danger arises. When a hedgehog sense danger, they will roll themselves up, leaving the spike at the back pointing outwards, thus protecting their vulnerable part and exposing the invulnerable part. If an enemy tries to attack them when they are in defensive mode, they will be injured by the spike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 2 hedgehogs out in the wild, meeting each other while wandering in the forest they live in when looking for shelter. It is almost winter, near the end of the autumn season. Both of the hedgehogs feel very cold walking alone out in the wild due to the cold ambient temperature. Looking into each other eyes, they decide to hug with each other to preserve the warm of their body. Here, the dilemma arises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-12/hedgehog-dilemma.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hedgehog Dilemma&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If both of the hedgehogs hug with each other, the spike on their body will hurt each other. Doing otherwise however would simply mean suffering the freezing sensation from the loss of body temperature. Either choice they make, they will hurt each other regardlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A human does not simply hurt each other physically by standing close to each other, but the same happens to a human in the psychology level. Human tend to hurt each other when they get too close. This is contributed by a lot of factors, one which includes taken for granted for each other beings. We tend to appreciate more for a person who is nice to you compare to someone who is very close to you. This is because when someone close to us does us something good, it is just another day where they are being good to us. The same does not apply to someone who is not very close to us, where when they does us something good, it is not usual, not just another day, and it is a special day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are also other factors that contribute to the hedgehog dilemma. When two humans have a very close relationship with each other, expectation would be different for both of them. The way they treat each other would also be different at the very same time. Different attitude will take place, and the relationship looks as if it had transformed into something that is completely different from when their relationship gets started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, we had only considered the situation where seemingly can be avoided with good training on handling relationship with other people, setting the right expectation, not taken for granted, etc. Let’s consider a situation where the relationship happens across a pair of enlightened individuals. These two individuals are extremely well versed with psychology. They are also extremely good in interpersonal communication skills. However, conflict may still arise due to misunderstanding. So long as these two individuals remain two different individuals, they will have different thoughts, a different definition of words and required to exchange thought by using any form of signs. It is not until both of them become a single person, conflicts will always arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it simply, hedgehog dilemma is a dilemma where despite goodwill appear between two or more individuals, conflicts will still happen, and it is the nature of human interaction itself. Each and every one of us has different thoughts, a different definition of words, different personality and different ways of expressing ourselves. All of these could easily lead to conflicts. All of these had yet take into consideration where people with bad will exists. Conflicts arise due to the selfishness of these people. Selfish by itself is not necessarily inherently bad things, but it can be undesirable when it is done in a way that it affects other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the anime, various conflicts arise throughout the whole journey. These conflicts often arise even when all of them have goodwill by helping each other to sustain in the bounty hunter business. Although the reason they do it is so that in turn they have a higher probability in sustaining themselves in the business, it would consider as goodwill here because it is a win-win situation. One of the examples would be when the protagonist, Spike, wanted to go when he overheard an operation name to be his lover name. His partner, out of good will, knowing that going there would bring nothing good to him, trying to stop him, yet eventually end up as an argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In real life, we often have conflicts with our family and friends. Conflicts can arise with matters as small as some small habit to education path or career choice. Our family has a different set of experience, more so especially for you and your parents. They live through different times, different eras, and a different set of culture apply to them compare to yours. They have a very different thought due to the environment around them that they have lived through. The career choice in the past is obvious where you are either doctor, engineer, lawyer or disgrace to the family. The same might not apply in today’s world. However, we cannot deny the fact that their concern is nevertheless out of goodwill. These conflicts simply arise due to different experience between you and your family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In business, there are a lot of cases where one become good friends with their client. When they get very close in relationship, people tend to treat each other as normal friends instead of a professional. These can eventually lead to conflicts due to expectations.  For an employer-employee relationship, when conflicts happen at non work hour, these conflicts can bring over to work hour, which in turn negatively affect the outcome of work. These can be avoided for individuals who are good and handling conflicts and able to separate personal and work matter, not bringing such vibe into work hours, however, most people don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/post/2018-12/smart-memes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, conflicts happen so long as one cannot know what others think, and everyone remains as a separate entity. So, is there a way to avoid conflicts? Maybe, if interaction does not happen in the very first place, no conflicts will take place. Se-mat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart, not so smart, humans being is essentially a social animal. A human being needs other human beings in order to survive their day to day routine. In hunter-gatherer tribe, one need another human being to take care of some of their needs, while they take care of other needs of another human being. For instance, some of the people in the tribe will be a weapon maker, some will be a hunter, some will be fruits collector and many more. A hunter cannot live on their own. They need weapons that made by weapon maker and fruits collected by fruits collector when they are not able to make a hunt for that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That goes even without saying for today’s world. The device that you are using to read this post, the chair you are sitting on or the bed you are lying on, the clothes that you are wearing, the eyeglasses if you are wearing one, the lighting device that light up the room that you are in, the fan or air-conditioning that brings down the temperature of the place where you are in, the electricity that delivered to your place in order to power whatever you need it to and the very house or building that you are in, all of these is the product of thousands, if not millions of people, ranging from the scientists who took research in order to discover new concepts and hence making whatever you have possible, the engineer who engineer these concepts to what is it now, the workers who work to obtain raw material needed to construct whatever end product, the factory worker who assemble different parts into the actual final product, the lorry driver who deliver these products to the stores which sell them, the promoter who sells the product, and the list goes on. A simple pencil that you uses every single day can involve thousands of people. To say you need no human interaction is to say living in the wild alone, getting your own foods, drinks, and shelter, living a self-sufficient life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have interactions is to have conflicts, to not to have interactions is to go back to a fully self-sufficient life. Our life cannot avoid from neither human interaction nor conflict. Human interaction and conflict perhaps is an essential part of human life. Here, we had only cover physiological needs. We had yet dive into the realm of psychological needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are social animal not just from the perspective of the physiological needs, but also psychological needs. We need other human beings to interact with. We need to express our thought, our opinion, our stress. We also need other human beings to comfort us and letting us know that we are not alone. By simply knowing that we are not alone, this can be easily turned into strength and motivation to overcome whatever obstacle we are facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example from the Anime would be the episode where when Spike insists on pursuing a transaction with the code name of his lover. His partner trying to stop him, knowing that nothing good will turns out. Yet, eventually, it turns into an argument. his partner asking him not to come back once he went out, stating that he only letting him stay because he thinks that Spike is lonely. Spike, in turn, telling him that he stay simply because he thinks that his partner is the one who is lonely. After leaving, both of them feel nostalgic for the time they spend together. They both think each other feels lonely simply because they themselves know how it feels to be lonely, hence able to understand each other. It might happen subconsciously, not knowing that thinking each other feels lonely simply because they themselves, too, are lonely. Eventually, they realize it, when both of them start feeling lonely themselves and feel nostalgic for the time they spend together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what a lot of people do is to keep a certain distance with other people in order to maintain the best relationship possible. Like the hedgehog, hugging each other would mean hurting each other, while leaving each other would be freeze to death in the cold, staying in a close distance that enough for heat exchange yet not hurting each other would be the best for both parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In business, keeping a certain distance would mean treating each other as professionals and not turn into close friend and in turn to have a different set of expectation compare to a close friend. Employer keeping a certain distance with an employee will avoid bringing the vibe of conflicts in personal space into work time due to each individual treating each other as professional. A boundary is being drawn, and that is the boundary which keeps each other in best interest possible. While getting too close in a relationship can break the relationship apart, yet we need to have some relationships at all, keeping a relationship certain distance at the same time would mean letting the relationship the closest possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, exceptions do happen. One can maintain a close relationship without breaking apart when both individuals are enlightened individuals. The ultimate goals here is to train ourselves into an enlightened individual, and able to have a close relationship with other enlightened individuals when meeting with one. To put it in hedgehog metaphor, it would be taking out the hedgehog outfit aside and hugging with each other thus getting the most out of heat preservation yet not hurting each other. As mention above, conflicts will still arise so long as these individuals are two separate entities, but an enlightened individual will be able to resolve this conflicts, and in turn, getting the relationship to even closer than ever. To turn conflicts into strengths thus is the ultimate goals of every relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My blog will end here, and if you have some spare time, I would surely recommend you to watch the anime. I assure you that you will not regret watching it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See You Space Cowboy…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I'm going there to find out if I'm really alive.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2018-12/spike.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">[Book] Review: No Longer Human</title><link href="/blog/book-no-longer-human-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Book] Review: No Longer Human" /><published>2018-12-09T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-12-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>/blog/book-no-longer-human-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/book-no-longer-human-review/">&lt;p&gt;人間失格, also known as No Longer Human is a book written by Osamu Dazai. It is a book that I bought last week (from the time of this writing) and also another book that I finish in 2 days. It is a really good book, and when I finish the book, I knew that I wanted to write a review of this book. This blog, unlike any other blogs that I had written before, is a review of the book instead of some very technical analysis on the subject being discussed. Part of the reason is that this book is believed to be a fictionize autobiography of the author himself as a lot of things happen on the protagonist happens on the author at some point of his life, and it is a story narrating how alienated he is from other people. Another reason is that while there is not a lot to analyze, feelings gain from reading the book is more important than trying to analyze and interpret it as correct as possible. What more important and charming in this book is to experience the character (or the author) feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book started with when the protagonist is still a child. When he is a child, he already has a sense of alienation from other people. This is partly due to a strict culture which Japanese stick on to. The protagonist, unable to understand the inference of these cultures, started to feel more and more distant from other people. This eventually leads to protagonist putting on a facade where he pretending to be a clown so he could avoid trouble with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vibe of alienation just goes on the whole book. In the book, Japanese culture sort of act as a very important part of the book, like how Japanese hold on to the pride of something above even relationship connected with blood. This, perhaps, also contribute to the process of alienation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the protagonist put on a facade where he pretending to be a clown. He will purposely learn the behavior or some comedian, learn the joke to tell people, or even purposely embarrass himself to achieve the comedy effect. There is one time when he is in high school, during physical education period, where they do some kind of pull up, he purposely fall on the floor so people could laugh at it. However, there is this one classmate who sees through him for putting on the facade. This makes him feel so scared that he tries to do a lot of things to get the person onto his side so that no people will know about him putting on the facade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened after that is he successfully make friend with the person. What very interesting about this book is the self-consciousness of the protagonist in the whole book. The protagonist is very conscious about his behavior of putting on the facade, every detail of inner thought that went through him, and he felt right after whatever happened. The thought process of the protagonist makes this book so interesting. It makes you not only able to see the face value of the story, but also from the first person perspective from the protagonist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very interesting to be able to see why the protagonist do what he does. Throughout the story, the protagonist knows that he is very attractive towards women. At one point in the novel, the protagonist is addicted to alcohol for escaping his existential vacuum. However, the protagonist runs out of money, yet he still went to one of the bars where he knows a woman inside is attracted to him to ask for sake. He went in, told the women he doesn’t have a single cents, and the woman treats him with sake and slept with the women after that. The thought process of the protagonist wanting to drink alcohol, thinking about those women which love him, and thinking about how to get alcohol and how he treats the women that love him, everything is just so interesting about this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most interesting of all is how he interacts with people that he knows where they are having the same alienation inner thought. It’s very hard to even imagine living such lives. Such precise inner thought might only be possible because these are exactly the same thought that the author had experience throughout his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there isn’t proof that the author had experienced the exact inner thought. However, many things that happen in the novel had happened to the author at one point in his life. In the novel, the protagonist attempt suicide with a woman by jumping into the river. The protagonist survived but the woman had died, and he is charged for accomplice suicide and disowned by his family. The very same thing happen to the author where he suicides with a bar hostess Shimeko Tanabe. The bar hostess died and he survives and is charged for accomplice suicide and disowned by family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point in the novel, the wife of the protagonist is raped by a stranger. In the novel, the protagonist saw it and did not take any action against that. The author’s wife committed adultery with one of his best friends when he is in a mental institution, and they commit double suicide after author finding out the events. There are a lot of similarities between the character and the author himself, and these are just 2 out of many examples. The lists of evidence can go on and I make no attempt to exhaust the evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it is a very interesting book. When the author finishes writing this book, he makes another attempt to suicide and finally succeeded upon numerous suicide attempt. Certainly, it is not a very happy book, but I think it is a very nice book to read and to be able to sort of experience a journey which is completely different from us. I rate this book 10/10, and if you are interested in this book, grab it from any bookstore or contact me and borrow from me and I would be happy to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last book written before a successfull suicide</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/post/2018-12/no-longer-human-photograph.jpg" /></entry></feed>